片名：享受吧! 一個人的旅行
我有個朋友叫黛博拉
她是個心理學家
l have a friend, Deborah,
a psychologist...
費城政府要求她.
...who was asked
by the city of Philadelphia...
為剛剛來到這裏的柬埔寨難民
...if she could offer psychological
counseling to Cambodian refugees...
和海上難民提供心理咨詢
...boat people,
who had recently arrived in the city.
黛博拉被嚇壞了
因為這些柬埔寨人
Deborah was daunted by the task.
These Cambodians...
經歷了種族屠殺和大饑荒
眼睜睜看著親人被殺害
...had suffered genocide, starvation,
relatives murdered before their eyes...
在難民營待過多年
悲慘地坐船逃到西方世界
...years in refugee camps,
harrowing boat trips to the West.
她怎麼能理解他們的感受?
How could she relate
to their suffering?
她怎麼能幫到這些人呢?
How could she help these people?
大家猜猜  這些難民和黛博拉
So guess what all these people
wanted to talk about...
我這位心理學家朋友  談得最多的是什麼...
...with my friend Deborah,
the psychologist.
幾乎都是"我是在難民營遇見他的
lt was all,
"l met this guy in the refugee camp.
我覺得他真的很愛我 但分開了以後
I thought he really loved me,
but when we got separated...
他和我表妹好上了
現在他還說他愛我
...he took up with my cousin.
Now he says he loves me...
還老是打電話給我 他們已經結婚了
我該怎麼辦?"
...and keeps calling me. They're
married now. What should l do?"
因為大家都這樣
This is how we are.
有什麼我能幫您的嗎?
May I help you?
我是麗茲.吉爾伯特 我在寫一篇有關
巴里島的文章
I'm Liz Gilbert. I'm writing
a magazine article on Bali.
我想來見見一位巫醫
I wanted to meet a medicine man.
大家都跟我說我該見見科圖.賴爺 我來對地方了嗎?
Everyone said I should meet
Ketut Liyer. Am l in the right place?
等一下
Wait.
你瞧 現在我來到了這
見一個第九代傳人的巫醫
l mean, here I am with
a ninth-generation medicine man...
我該問他些什麼問題呢?
...and what do I wanna
ask him about?
如何走近上帝?
Getting closer to God?
怎麼拯救全世界挨餓的兒童?
Saving the world's
starving children?
很高興見到你 我是科圖.賴爺
Happy to see you. l am Ketut Liyer.
才不 我要和他說說我的戀愛史
Nope. l wanna discuss
my relationship.
你在全世界旅行
You are a world traveler.
你會活很長一段時間
You will live a long time...
交到很多朋友 擁有許多人生體驗
...have many friends,
many experiences.
你會結兩次婚 一次很長 一次很短
You will have two marriages.
One long, one short.
我現在的是長的還是短的?
Am l in the long one
or the short one?
天機不可泄露
Can't tell.
你還會變成窮光蛋
Also you will lose all your money.
就在未來六到十個月內
I think in next six to 1 0 months.
不過別擔心 你會掙回來的
Don't worry.
You will get it all back again.
而且你還會回到巴里島
And you will come back to Bali...
住大概三四個月 教我英語
...and live here for three or four
months and teach me English.
我一直找不到人和我練英語
I never had anybody
to practice my English with.
然後...
And then...
我會把我懂的都教給你
...l will teach you everything l know.
等等
Wait.
這個給你
I have this for you.
要腳踏實地
你就會感覺有四條腿
Keep grounded so it's like
you have four legs.
這樣你就能好好停留在這個世界
That way, you can stay in this world.
還有 不要用你的頭腦看這個世界
Also, no looking at world
through your head.
用你的心看
Look through your heart instead.
這樣你才能瞭解上帝
That way, you will know God.
這就是你來這裏的原因吧?
Which is why you came here, no?
後會有期了  小鱷魚(俏皮話)
See you later, alligator.
六個月後
我校對了她所有的手稿
I proofread all of her manuscripts.
我老婆非常非常漂亮
不過她拼不來單詞
My wife is very, very beautiful,
but she can't spell for anything.
看 是史蒂芬叔叔
Look at Uncle Stephen.
還有麗茲阿姨
And Auntie Liz.
我正掐表計算這聚會什麼時候結束
我就能回去穿上大號褲子了
I'm counting the minutes for this to be
over so l can get in my big girl pants.
你看起來太棒了 你才剛生完孩子
You look fantastic.
You just had a baby.
哦 你騙我 我肥死了 還累得要死
Oh, you're lying.
I'm fat, I'm exhausted...
腦子裏就不能有兩個想法並存
我覺得自己就像麗莎明妮莉
...l can't keep two thoughts.
I feel like Liza Minnelli.
史蒂芬 你能抱著傑克嗎?
Stephen, can you hold Jack?
- 我來給你介紹華特
- 好的
-l'm gonna introduce you to Walter.
-Yeah.
嘿 老兄 去喝個酒樂一樂?
Hey, dude, you wanna grab a beer
or something?
我的新書四月份會出來 多謝關心
My new book comes out in April.
Thank you for asking.
- 很好
- 是五月
-Great.
-May.
五月 五月
May. May.
這是安德烈 你們倆可是《時代》雜誌
最出名的候選人啊
This is Andre. You two are
Times' Most Notable nominees.
- 很高興總算認識你
- 我也是
-So glad to finally meet you.
-Nice to finally meet you.
我餵了他玉米脆餅 沒關係吧?
I fed him nachos. ls that bad?
你看起來很舒服嘛
你給他吃了什麼 麻醉藥?
You look comfortable.
What'd you feed him, chloroform?
- 來讓你爸爸抱吧
- 我說了 是玉米脆餅
-Give him to his dad.
-l told you, nachos.
知道嗎? 我要是被這麼顛過來
倒過去也會睡著的
Know what? I'd be asleep too
if l had a dump like that.
- 到媽媽那里去吧
- 過來
-We'll give him to his mom.
-Come here then.
- 來幫我換尿布?
- 好的
-Wanna help me change his diaper?
-Yes, I do.
嘿 古董車銷售怎麼樣了?
Hey, how's the vintage car
thing going?
哦 不 不 不 我換工作了
我現在是糕點師
Oh, no, no, no. l changed jobs.
I'm a pastry chef now.
- 你意思你現在烤麵包去了
- 是的
-You mean you're a baker.
-Yeah.
想來烤一下不?(吸大麻之意)
You wanna get baked?
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
很難受啊 是不是?
It's hard, isn't it?
哦 沒有 這樣多好玩啊
Oh, no. This is so much fun.
你還記得自己是什麼時候想生孩子的?
Did you know the exact moment
you wanted to have a baby?
不記得了 但是在我結婚之前
就拿到那盒子了
I can't remember, but l've had the box
since before l got married.
什麼盒子?
What box?
很小女生的 太丟人了
跟你說你會笑話我的
It's girly and embarrassing,
and you'll laugh at me if I tell you.
我會的 不過你還是得告訴我
I will laugh at you,
but you still have to tell me.
好吧
Come on.
床底下
Under the bed.
我一直把各種小寶寶的東西放進去
I've been filling it with baby things...
等待著安迪想做父親的那一天
...waiting until Andy
was ready to be a father.
太可愛了
So sweet.
這件有我的尺寸嗎?
Does this come in my size?
我也有個跟這一樣的盒子
不過裏面裝的都是國家地理雜誌
I have a box just like this, except
it's filled with National Geographics...
和時代週刊的旅行篇
...and The Times travel section.
裏面是所有我在死之前想去的地方
All the places l wanna see
before l die.
麗茲 生個孩子就像在臉上紋身
Liz, having a baby is like
getting a tattoo on your face.
你差不多要全身心投入
You kind of wanna be
fully committed.
所以我下個禮拜去阿魯巴島
只是一些很基礎的安排
So my trip to Aruba next week,
which is just a basic, you know...
睡哪啦 去游泳啦 品嘗美食...
..."where to sleep, swim
and stuff your face" piece....
我還買了件新的比基尼
I got a new bikini.
然後我就發現自己可以
無限制使用客房冰箱
And it turns out,
I have unlimited minibar access.
- 你懂什麼意思吧?
- 時差反應?
-You know what that means?
-Jet lag?
你 和我
You, me...
...盡情享用夏威夷果實
...macadamia nuts.
不錯啊
That was cute.
你知道我剛在聚會上聊天的那個人
讓我挺佩服的...
You know who l was talking to
at the party who was really inspiring...
- 布萊恩  - 塔拉的朋友
- Brian
-...was Tara's friend.
就是布萊恩 太不可思議了
他是個老師 你知道嗎?
Brian. Unbelievable.
He's a teacher, you know that?
是代課老師吧?
He's a substitute teacher, isn't he?
對 他跟我聊起現在教育費用的預算縮減
Yeah. He was talking about the
budget cuts that are happening now.
學校幾乎一分錢也沒有了
There's no money for anything.
音樂課取消了 藝術課取消了
There's no music classes,
there's no arts classes.
現在他們只能在課後義務教這些課
They're volunteering their time
to do all of this after school.
就是他們這些人在教我們的孩子
你知道嗎?
They're educating our kids,
you know?
你會是個好老師的 親愛的
I think you'd make
a great teacher, honey.
謝謝 不過其實我在想
Thank you,
but I was thinking more of like...
回學校繼續學習 拿到碩士學位
...education. Getting my masters,
going back to school. l don't know.
你覺得呢?
You know?
我...
I-- You know....
- 回到學校哦
- 我就是想到什麼說什麼
-Going back to school.
-l'm just thinking out loud.
我有個不祥的預感
覺得科圖的預言正在成真
I was getting the sinking feeling that
Ketut's prophecy was coming true.
現在是不是我那段短暫的婚姻?
Was l in the shorter marriage?
我們一年前才買了這棟房子
We'd only bought this house
a year ago.
這不是我想要的生活嗎?
Hadn't I wanted this?
我積極熱切地參與到這段生活的
I had actively participated
in every moment of the creation...
...無時無刻都積極
...of this life.
那為什麼我還覺得不是生活在其中?
So why didn't I see myself
in any of it?
唯一比留下來更不可思議的事情是...
The only thing more impossible
than staying...
...離開
...was leaving.
我不想傷害任何人
只想從後門悄悄溜走
I didn't wanna hurt anybody. l wanted
to slip quietly out the back door...
不停地奔向格陵蘭
...and not stop running
until l reached Greenland.
不過 我做了個相反的決定
lnstead, l made a decision.
祈禱
To pray.
其實就是 和上帝對話
You know, like, to God.
對我來說這事太過怪異
一開始我居然是這麼說的
And it was such a foreign concept to
me, that l swear l almost began with:
我很崇拜您的工作
"l'm a big fan of your work."
你好 上帝?
Hello, God?
很高興認識你 我...
Nice to finally meet you. l....
很抱歉以前從來沒直接跟你說過話...
I am sorry l've never spoken
directly to you before...
但是...
...but...
我希望我已經向你表示過...
...l hope l've expressed my...
對於你在我的生活中...
...ample gratitude for all
the blessings you've given...
所給予的幸福的感激...
...to me in my life.
我現在有大麻煩了
I'm in serious trouble.
我不知道該怎麼辦
I don't know what to do.
我需要答案
I need an answer.
請求你告訴我該怎麼做
Please, tell me what to do.
哦 上帝 幫幫我 拜託
Oh, God, help me, please.
告訴我該怎麼辦 我會照辦的
Tell me what to do and l'll do it.
回床上睡覺 麗茲
Go back to bed, Liz.
我不想去阿魯巴島
I don't wanna go to Aruba.
我不想要婚姻
I don't wanna be married.
《誰動了我的奶酪》
《不幸到幸福》
樓下有一整櫃有關離婚的書
You know, there's a whole
divorce section downstairs.
- ''胡椒研磨機''
- 她現在正處於
-"Pepper grinder."
-She's having...
- 精神崩潰之中
- 女人就是這樣的
-...a nervous breakdown.
-This is what girls do.
- 她在自我處理
- 她幹嘛不去喝個爛醉或找人上床?
-She's processing.
-Why doesn't she get drunk or laid?
如果你離開我我就會這麼干
That's what l would do if you left me.
不 你不會的
No, you wouldn't.
- 嗯 我不會的
- 她搬了出來 和法庭申請離婚
-No, I wouldn't.
-She moved out, she filed for divorce.
他們在一起八年了 她沒其他地方去
They were together eight years.
She's got no home.
''遺產''
"Legacy."
每個意大利單詞就像一塊巧克力糖
一個魔術
Every word in Italian is like a truffle.
A magic trick.
親愛的我懂 現在它是你的救生筏
Honey, l get it.
It's your life raft right now.
我和安迪離婚兩個星期後
我買了架織布機
When Andy and l broke up
for two weeks, l bought a loom.
我居然買了架要命的織布機
他居然要搞微釀啤酒
A frigging loom.
And he tried to start a microbrewery.
我不知道你們現在有多討厭我
反正我自己都討厭自己
I don't know how you guys
aren't sick of me now. I'm sick of me.
說什麼呢? 我們喜歡和你在一起
Are you kidding me?
We love having you.
就像我們有個駐家作家一樣
It's kind of like having
a writer in residence.
可你是個作家 你應該寫點什麼
But you are a writer.
You should be writing something.
也許我可以寫寫一個去意大利
學意大利語的女人
Maybe I could write about a woman
who goes to Italy to learn ltalian.
書名就叫《碳水化合物和變位動詞》
Call it
Carbohydrates and Conjugations.
我要自己找個地方住了
I'll start looking for a place.
- 我愛上你了
- 我不是你以為的那個人
-l'm falling in love with you.
-l'm not who you think I am.
我只是你的幻想
I'm just your fantasy.
不 瞎說 你是真實的
No, that's bullshit. You're real.
你的傷痕 你的才華
Your scars, your talent.
事實上 我不過只有一個爛酒吧...
The fact that
I own a piece-of-crap bar...
你卻能接受我只有這點能耐
...and you accept that
that's all l'm gonna do.
得了 這太爛了
Okay, this sucks.
- 我同意
- 別這麼無情
-l second that.
-Don't be rude.
我愛你的痛楚
I love your pain.
當我們在一起的時候
我很高興能抹去你的痛楚
And l love that when we're together,
I can make it go away.
- 哦 他演得不錯
- 你的愛...
-Oh, he's good.
-You're love...
- 他是很帥 但不代表他演技好
- ...就像熱麵包
-He's hot, there's a difference.
-...is like a hot panini.
當我看著你的眼睛
我能聽到海豚在擊掌輕拍
And when I look into your eyes,
I hear dolphins clapping.
那句話不是我寫的
I did not write that line.
他所不知道的是
Here's what he doesn't know yet.
我消失在了我愛的人之中
I disappear into the person l love.
我就是一層滲透膜 如果我愛你
你就能得到所有
I am the permeable membrane.
If l love you, you can have it all.
我的金錢 我的時間 我的身體
My money, my time, my body...
我的狗 我狗的金錢
...my dog, my dog's money.
我將承擔你的債務 對你投注
I will assume your debts
and project upon you...
所有你從未擁有過的俏皮可愛
...all sorts of nifty qualities you've
never actually cultivated in yourself.
我會給你這所有甚至更多
I will give you all this and more...
直到我精疲力竭耗盡自己
...until l am so exhausted
and depleted...
只有一種方法我能復原
...the only way l can recover...
就是迷上另一個人
...is by becoming infatuated
with someone else.
- 伊莉莎白 嗨
- 嗨
-Elizabeth, hi.
-Hi.
哦 真的嗎?
Oh, really?
你好嗎?
How you doing?
乾杯
Cheers.
- 謝謝
- 我該和你說聲對不起
-Thank you.
-l owe you an apology.
- 我走神了
- 沒有 我不是人見人愛的那型
-For the walkouts.
-Well, l'm not everyone's cup of tea.
我很懷疑
I doubt that.
我呢 另一方面來說 就是坨屎
I, on the other hand, was shit.
- 雖然我很努力在演了
- ''屎''這個字重了
-Although l was trying very hard.
-"Shit" is a strong word.
多謝
Thank you.
你真人看起來比在台上矮一點
You seem shorter in person
than on the stage.
- 是嗎? 我老聽人這麼說
- 對不起
-Really? l hear that a lot.
-Sorry.
沒關係
It's okay.
當一個陌生人比自己能更清楚地
It's unnerving when...
看清自己時 讓人非常緊張
...a total stranger sees you
more clearly than you see yourself.
我說你矮是這個意思
That's what l mean
by saying you're short.
是不是現在聽到海豚的擊掌輕拍了?
Are you hearing dolphins clapping
right now?
我剛才看到你就冒昧自己編了那句
I took a few liberties
with your material.
現在我允許你盡情來取笑我
我知道你一定很想
I give you full permission to make
fun of me. I know you're dying to.
你太迷人了 我都不知道怎麼取笑你
You're far too charming
to make fun of.
還是海豚的擊掌輕拍
I'm still hearing them.
這是你的精神導師嗎?
Is that your guru?
你逗我的吧 不過 是的
You're joking, but, yes, it is.
她很美
She's beautiful.
嗯 一個朋友跟我說起的
Yeah. A friend told me about her.
當時我失業 極度渴望點寄托
I was out of work and feeling
pretty desperate for something.
不是我最近一次失業 是更之前的
Not the last time I was out of work,
the time before that.
我有一種感覺 我找的地方都不對
And l just had this feeling like
I was looking in all the wrong places.
找什麼?
Looking for what?
上帝
God.
她在印度有個修行的地方
我一直很想去 可是
She has an ashram in India.
I'm dying to go, but...
你知道啦 一定要達到一定級別
好像三級肝炎什麼的
...you know, you have to get, like,
three stages of hepatitis shots...
而且我的保險費總是透支
...and my insurance always runs out.
等時機成熟我就去
I'll go when the time's right.
她的徒弟每天早晨都聚會
There's a gathering of her students
every morning.
如果你願意 我想帶你去
If you want,
I could take you sometime.
如果你不會因為100個
唸著梵文的人緊張不安的話
If you're not unnerved by 100
crunchy people chanting in Sanskrit.
我需要緊張不安
I need to be unnerved.
大衛 來自紐約郊區的瑜伽信徒
David. A yogi from Yonkers.
其實我並沒有愛上他
I didn't exactly fall in love
with the guy.
我只是跳出了自己的婚姻
What happened was
I dove out of my marriage...
投入了大衛的懷抱
...and into David's arms...
就像卡通裏的馬戲演員
...exactly the same way
a cartoon circus performer...
從高高的跳台上跳下
投入一個小水杯裏
...dives off a high platform
and into a small cup of water...
然後消失得無影無蹤
...vanishing completely.
你的小內衣 女王陛下
Your underwear, my queen.
他剛剛疊好了我的貼身衣物
He just folded my delicates.
哦 我的天 你有大麻煩了
Oh, my God, baby,
you are in so much trouble.
36樓?
Thirty-six?
我的委託人不想離婚
My client is simply not interested
in a divorce.
他是認真的?
Is he serious?
他真的要代表自己?
Is he really representing himself?
我可是上過一個學期的法學院的
One semester of law school
right here, baby.
很好 那怎麼才能
讓你的委託人想離婚呢?
Great. Well, what would it take
to interest your client?
好 這樣吧 你搞砸了我的生活
Okay, so here's the deal.
You have screwed up my life...
可是我想知道的是 你為什麼不能...
...but what l wanna know
is why couldn't you find yourself...
在我們的婚姻中找到你自己呢?
為什麼你不能說出自己的感受?
...in our marriage? Why didn't you
say what you were thinking?
- 我說了 你從來不聽我說話
- 不 你從來沒說過
-l did. You never listened to me.
-No. You never said:
''嘿 你知道嗎? 你爛透了
我非常非常得不快樂''
"Hey, you know what?
You suck. l'm deeply unhappy."
你只是起身離開 從來沒給我機會
來解決這些問題
You just took off. You never gave me
a chance to address those problems.
這不公平 你就這麼放棄了
我可是立了誓言的
That's not fair. That's just quitting.
I took vows.
死亡才能分開我們 我是認真的
Till death.
And l take them seriously.
我相信這只是一個階段
我們等一等就會過去的
I believe this is just a phase
and l'm willing to wait it out.
你總是在等待 史蒂芬
You are always waiting, Stephen.
等待我回家 等待我想要孩子...
Waiting for me to come home,
to wanna have kids...
等待我給你做晚飯
我不知道為什麼我們就不能接受...
...to make you dinner.
I don't know why we can't accept...
事實就是我們不想
再這麼不幸福地生活下去了
...we don't wanna live
in unhappiness anymore.
我承認我偶爾會讓你感覺靠不住
I accept the fact that
I am occasionally unreliable...
還經常分散注意力到別的事情上去
可我以為你就喜歡我這樣
...and l often get sidetracked,
but I thought you liked that about me.
我以為你就喜歡我擁有希望和理想
I thought it was okay
that I had hopes and dreams.
擁有理想 史蒂芬 很好 太好了
那就去實現啊 但只能選一樣
Have a dream. Stephen, great,
fine. Do that. Just pick one.
好 我選一樣 我選你
Okay, l pick one. I pick you.
我知道這很難受
I know this is awful.
但是我身體中的每一個分子都相信
你會找到那個...
But l believe with every molecule of
my body that you will find the person...
和你有共同理想的人
...that wants just what you want.
那個給予你所需要和值得的東西
而我不是那個人
That will give you what you want
and what you deserve. l'm not her.
顯然你根本不知道我需要什麼
Well, you obviously know nothing
about what l want.
我的委託人要呈上一首自編的歌曲
My client would like to submit
a song he wrote...
他認為此歌曲與本訴訟有關
這首歌是這樣的
...that he believes is relevant to these
proceedings. Goes something like this:
你開玩笑吧?
Are you kidding?
逃兵 逃兵 逃兵!
Quitter, quitter, quitter!
那算我錯了怎麼樣? 我不能再忍受
How about l take the blame?
I am the one who couldn't deal...
每個週末漫步在大型超市中...
...with another weekend roaming
some box-shaped superstore...
刷卡購買家用電器...
...buying appliances on credit...
假裝像別的夫妻一樣
其實我們都不知道什麼是婚姻
...and pretending to be a couple that
neither one of us ever knew how to be.
要買烤麵包機的人是你
You wanted that toaster.
你喜歡假裝 好吧 你很有耐力
我是失敗者 我不會假裝
"You like faking it, fine. You're stellar.
I'm the failure. l suck at faking it."
- 我表現得很潑婦
- 那現在事情進行到哪一步了?
-lt was not my finest hour.
-So where do things stand now?
我們準備提供所有財產的一半
We're prepared
to offer half of everything...
以及我委託人的退休賬戶
...and my client's retirement accounts.
都拿走吧 全給你
Take it all then. Everything.
他還是拒絕
He still said no.
- 他現在一定很恨我
- 他不恨你
-He hates me now.
-He doesn't hate you.
他只是心碎了
His heart is broken.
我覺得他恨你
I think he hates you.
小心我永遠把你鎖進地下室
I'm never letting you
out of the basement.
我們下周看事情怎麼樣了再談吧?
Why don't we talk next week
and we'll see where things stand?
- 好的
- 這種事情總有...
-Okay.
-These things have a way...
解決之道的
...of working themselves out.
你怎麼會成為素食主義者的?
So why'd you become a vegetarian?
有一次我看到好多牛被殺掉
I saw some cows slaughtered
one time.
基本沒吃晚飯啊
Barely touched your dinner.
他才28歲
He's 28.
這對他來說太苛刻了是吧?
那你呢?
This is hard for him, isn't it?
And you?
冥想挺有用的
The meditations help.
麗茲
Liz.
還記得幾年前
你廢寢忘食地...
You remember a couple of years ago,
when you threw yourself into...
重新裝修你家廚房?
當時看你...
...the renovation of your kitchen?
You were consumed...
多像個完美的妻子和家庭煮婦啊
...with being the perfect wife and cook.
我那只是試圖讓生活有點起色
I was trying to make it work.
那我認為頌歌和冥想也一樣...
Well, l think chanting and meditation
is the same thing...
...只是形式不同罷了
...in a different costume.
一定要把那紀錄片給我看看
Definitely give me that documentary.
我一直在考慮素食的問題
I've been thinking
about vegetarianism.
我的脂肪肝比屋頂都高了
My triglycerides
are through the roof.
沒問題 謝謝款待
Yeah. Thanks for everything.
我們也很高興
Great to meet you.
- 怎麼了?
- 沒什麼 只是...
-What?
-Nothing. lt's just...
...你過去看起來有點像史蒂芬
...you know,
you used to look like Stephen.
現在你看起來像大衛了
Now you kind of look like David.
懂我的意思嗎?
You know?
我想說的是 這跟人和自己的狗狗
越長越像差不多
What l meant was, you know how
people start resembling their dogs?
他這麼說是什麼意思
我們長得像同一隻狗?
Why would he say that,
we look like the same dog?
- 他在開玩笑
- 不好笑
-He was joking.
-Not funny.
他喝了五罐海尼根 喝醉了
Well, he had five Heinekens.
He was bombed.
一點都不好笑
Well, not funny.
我們不可能像同樣的狗
We don't look like the same dog.
就算是 你就是牧羊犬
我則是藏獒
If anything, you're a collie
and l'm a Tibetan mastiff.
別讓我做只能想念你的人
Don't you wanna give me a chance
to miss you.
起初你愛慕的對象...
It begins when
the object of your affection...
帶給你如魔幻般醉人的...
...bestows upon you
a heady hallucinogenic dose...
你連想都不敢想的東西...
...of something you've never
even dared to admit you wanted...
...情感的興奮劑
帶給你如狂風暴雨般的愛和激情
...an emotional speedball
of thunderous love and excitement.
很快你開始渴望
近乎癡迷地渴望那種關注...
Soon you start craving that attention
with the hungry obsession...
...如同上癮一般
...of any junkie.
當愛慕不再
你變得鬱鬱寡歡 神經質 更不用提...
When it's withheld, you turn sick,
crazy, not to mention resentful...
對使你陷入如此地步的人怨恨不已...
...of the dealer who encouraged
this addiction in the first place...
...而眼中已看不到美好的事物
...but now refuses to pony up
the good stuff.
我只是鬱悶 關心你而已
我就是不明白
Just frustrated, l'm concerned.
I don't understand.
你不懂什麼?
What don't you get?
到底怎麼回事?
你不再看著我的眼睛
What's going on?
You don't look me in the eye.
- 你沒...
- 沒人讓你整理床
-You don't finish your--
-Nobody's asking you to make the bed!
- 你不再跟我做愛!
- 有時候我沒性趣!
-You don't have sex with me!
-Sometimes I'm not in the mood!
真該死 他過去都是免費給的
Goddamn him, and he used to
give it to you for free.
接下來你發現
瘦弱的自己在角落裏發抖...
Next stage finds you skinny,
shaking in a corner...
...心想只要能再一次
擁有那種感覺...
...certain only that
you'd sell your soul...
...就算是靈魂你也願意出賣
...just to have that one thing
one more time.
那為什麼我們不談談?
攤開來說清楚?
Well, then why don't we discuss it?
Why don't we sort it?
- 為什麼不能像成年人一樣?
- 那好 我能有一點自己的空間嗎?
-Why don't we act like adults?
-Okay. Can I have a little space?
- 怎麼樣?
- 同時...
-How about that?
-Meanwhile...
...你愛慕的對象被你排擠
...the object of your adoration
is now repulsed by you.
- 你也不是總讓我感到難受的
- 真是安慰到我了
-You don't always make me miserable.
-There's a comfort.
我只是...偶爾回到家...
I just-- Sometimes l need to
come home...
...需要一些獨處的時間
...and have a little David time.
他看著你如同陌生人
He looks at you like someone
he's never met before.
- 這可以嗎?
- 噢 那真是不錯啊
-ls that okay?
-Yeah. No, it's fine.
我沒必要為這辯解
And not have to, like, you know,
justify it.
諷刺的是你卻不能責怪他
The irony is
you can hardly blame him.
因為看看自己吧 一團糟
I mean, check yourself out.
You're a mess.
即使你都無法認出自己
Unrecognizable
even to your own eyes.
你叫我搬過來
我來了
You asked me to come here?
Here l am.
但事情變了 不再是那樣了
And it turned into something else.
- 對吧?
- 你真是太幼稚了
-Didn't it?
-You are such a child.
- 好吧 我不想再這樣下去了
- 很好 太好了
-Right. I can't take this anymore.
-Great. Perfect.
你這樣真是有責任感啊
That's a great response
to a conversation.
見鬼
Goddamn it.
你最後來到了癡迷的最終階段
You have now reached
infatuation's final destination.
不帶一絲憐憫的自我貶低
The complete
and merciless devaluation of self.
你要走一年?
You wanna go away for a year?
你知道我今早醒來是什麼感覺嗎 迪莉亞?
Do you know what I felt
when l woke up, Delia?
什麼都沒有 沒有激情 沒有活力
沒有信仰 沒有靈感 一丁點都沒有
Nothing. No passion, no spark,
no faith, no heat. Absolutely nothing.
我必須得擺脫這種可怕的情況
I've gotten past the point where
I can be calling this a bad moment.
我被嚇死了 天啊
這比死了還可怕...
And it just terrifies me. Jesus,
this is like worse than death to me...
...一想到從今以後我將一直如此
...the idea that this is the person
I'm gonna be from now on.
知道嗎 人人都這樣
You know what, This happens to people.
他們20幾歲墜入愛河
結婚生子...
They fall in love in their 20s,
get married...
...30幾歲買下帶花園和廚房的屋子...
...do the granite countertop,
white-picket fence in their 30s...
...又突然之間意識到
"我不應該這樣"
...and somewhere they realize,
"This is not for me."
然後他們意志消沉 覺得身處地獄
但還是得打起精神...
So they fail and they fall down,
they hurt like hell, they straighten up...
...到壓抑的辦公室來上班
...and march their asses
to the shrink's office.
- 沒人能一走了事
- 我沒有一走了事
-They can't just check out.
-l am not checking out.
我是需要改變
I need to change.
這裏有支持你的人 麗茲
You have a support system
here, Liz.
你有愛你的朋友和親人
You have friends and family
who love you.
你感覺到我對你的愛和支持了嗎  沒有吧
And do you feel my love for you?
My support for you? No.
什麼都沒有 我就像個死人
There's, like, nothing. l have no pulse.
- 我要去意大利
- 意大利 為什麼去意大利?
-l am going to Italy.
-ltaly. Why ltaly?
- 你午餐吃的什麼?
- 不記得了 沙拉吧
-What did you have for lunch?
-l don't know. A salad.
就是這樣 我以前對食物對人生
也是這種態度...
Exactly. l used to have this appetite
for food, for my life...
...現在都沒了
...and it is just gone.
我要去那些能讓我感到驚艷的地方
I wanna go someplace
where l can marvel at something.
語言 意大利冰淇淋
意大利麵 或是其它什麼
Language, gelato,
spaghetti, something.
- 你說起話來像個學生
- 我也要像個學生那樣做
-You're talking like a college kid.
-l've been acting like one.
從我15歲開始 我要麼在談戀愛
要麼在分手
Since I was 15, I've either been
with a guy or breaking up with a guy.
從未有過兩個星期的空閒...
I have not given myself
two weeks of a breather...
...去好好的考慮下自己
...to just deal with, you know, myself.
你跟大衛怎麼了?
What's going on
with you and David?
怎麼了 掉到床下了?
What, did you fall out?
我不知道如何適應這里
I don't know how to be here.
你想知道怎麼適應這里?
別在一直期待什麼了
You wanna know how to be here?
Stop constantly waiting for something.
我要先去意大利 之後去
大衛的精神導師在印度的靜修處
I'm going to Italy and then l'm going
to David's guru's ashram in lndia...
...這一年的最後我會去巴里島
...and l'm going to end the year
in Bali.
這就是我的計劃
That's what l'm gonna do.
真是難以辯駁
那沙灘真是不錯 但是為什麼?
That's harder to argue with.
The beaches are nice. But why?
- 科圖跟我說過
- 那個沒有牙齒的傢伙
-Ketut told me I would.
-Guy with no teeth.
但你處於絕望之中...
When you're desperate...
...有這麼一個人
沒錯 他看起來是有點像尤達大師
...and some guy who,
yes, looks a little like Yoda...
...遞給你這樣一個預言
不得不相信點什麼
...hands you a prophecy,
you have to respond.
- 抗抑鬱藥要麼?
- 肯定
-Do you need a Xanax?
-Always.
好吧 我就說一句
說完這一句就不說了
Okay, l'm just gonna say it.
I'm gonna say it and be done with it.
如果沒用怎麼辦?
What if it doesn't work?
我整個人生就這樣裝進了
12平方英尺大小的隔間裏
My whole life
fits in a 1 2-foot-square box.
你知道這話我一天要聽幾次嗎?
You know how many times
I hear that in a day?
其中大部分人再也沒回來過
Most of them never come back
for their whole life.
- 麗茲  - 你好?
- Liz
-Hello?
好消息 史蒂芬剛簽了離婚協議
Good news. Stephen just signed
the divorce papers.
我或許一周之後就回來了
身無分文又得了痢疾
I'll probably be back in a week,
penniless with dysentery.
你是我的偶像
You're my hero.
嘿
Hey.
如果你留下來
我們每晚都去吃印度菜吧
If you stay,
we'll go out for lndian every night.
你從未叫我留下來
You never asked me to stay.
走 走 走
Go, go, go.
你知道最好笑的是什麼?
You know what's funny?
這是我人生中第一次
沒人在家等我回來
This is the first time in my life
there's no one waiting at home for me.
我連個可以回的家都沒有
I don't even have a home
to come back to.
老天 你會交到新朋友的
Oh, God. You'll make friends.
你會跟背包客們交朋友
You'll make friends with a backpack,
of course.
出去走走總是好的
It'd be great to get away.
我和安迪曾討論在佛羅倫薩
找間小別墅住一個月
Andy and l were talking about getting
a little villa in Florence for a month.
你知道的 十年後
當傑克長大點...
You know, and in 10 years,
when Jack is older....
怎麼了啊?
What?
你知道我為什麼會這麼阻撓你嗎?
You know why l was giving you
such a hard time?
我愛的工作 老公 孩子
但是...
I love my job, my guy and my kid,
but....
我也希望我能出去走走
I wish I could go.
我愛你 我為你感到驕傲
I love you and l'm proud of you.
現在 快走吧
Now go.
有個很老的意大利笑話 說得是...
There is a wonderful
old Italian joke...
有個窮人每天都去教堂...
...about a poor man
who goes to church every day...
在一尊偉大的神像前祈禱說...
...and prays before the statue
of a great saint, begging:
"我敬愛的神啊 懇求你 懇求你
讓我中樂透獎吧"
"Dear saint, please, please, please
let me win the lottery."
最終 惱怒的神像動了起來...
Finally, the exasperated statue
comes to life...
低頭望著那祈禱的人說...
...and looks down at the begging man
and says:
"我的子民啊 也拜託你幫幫忙
先買張彩卷吧"
"My son, please, please, please
buy a ticket."
現在我算是聽懂這個笑話了
So now l get the joke.
我買了三張
And l've got three tickets.
你在爐子上把水加熱
You heat the water on the stove.
那如果我想洗澡...?
So if I want to bathe...?
你把水倒進浴盆
You put the water in the tub.
好吧
Okay.
這水看起來不夠洗澡
Yeah. lt doesn't really seem like
enough water to bathe in.
不夠
Not enough.
不 夠了
Yes, it's enough.
燒個三 四 五壺
Fill it up three, four, five times.
重要部位都可以洗乾淨了
Everything that's important
gets cleaned.
這個安全嗎? 這...
Is this safe? This...
...架子? 架...
...scaffolding? Scaffol--
這東西撐著天花板
It holds up the ceiling.
不然會塌的
Otherwise it will fall apart.
什麼都會壞掉 親愛的
Everything falls apart, my dear.
生命中唯一永恆的 是家庭
The only thing permanent in life
is family.
你還沒結婚
You're not married.
不 離婚了
No, divorziata.
為什麼離婚?
Why divorced?
我們搞砸了
We broke it.
你比從前快樂?
You're more happy now?
我有個規矩
I have one rule.
陌生男人不能在這過夜
No strange men spending the night.
你們這些美國女孩
到意大利來...
You American girls
when you come to ltaly...
...嘗嘗意大利麵...
...all you want is pasta...
...和意式香腸就好了
...and sausage.
我租了
I'll take it.
很好 眼光不錯
Good. You chose well.
卡布奇諾
Cappuccino.
- 這裏跟動物園差不多
- 我意大利語太差勁了
-lt's a zoo in here.
-And my ltalian sucks.
- 你來這裏多久了?
- 兩周了 你呢?
-How long have you been here?
-Two weeks. You?
六個星期了 你會學好的
Six weeks. You'll get better.
兩杯卡布奇諾 謝謝
Two cappuccinos, please.
牛奶這次要溫的
And warm the milk this time.
昨天差點燙著我的舌頭
Yesterday it was too hot
and burned my tongue.
- 你喜歡千層酥點心嗎?
- 當然
-You like Napoleons?
-Of course.
兩塊千層酥點心 謝謝
And two Napoleons, please.
你意大利語真厲害
Your Italian is fantastic.
我有個厲害的老師
如果你需要我可以把他的電話給你
I have a wonderful tutor.
I'll give you his number if you like.
- 他真的很不錯 而且需要份工作
- 噢 那太感謝了
-He's really good and he needs work.
-Oh, great.
你是荷蘭人? 還是德國人?
Are you Dutch? German?
瑞典人 比你想得
還要冷的地方來的
Swedish. Even colder people,
if you can imagine.
- 幸會 我是麗茲  - 蘇菲
-l'm Liz, by the way.
-Sofi.
你可以說
You can say:
過去式這麼說
It's past.
太快了 不過還行
Too fast, but okay.
你可以說
You can say:
噢
Yeah.
真是個美麗的詞
What a beautiful word.
沒什麼 只是"讓我們跨越過去"
很平常吧
Come on, it's "let's cross over."
It's so ordinary.
不 不 這是意大利語音節完美的組合
No, it's the perfect combination
of ltalian sounds.
有顫音 "ah"  有過渡的彈舌
還有滑音"ess"
It's the wistful "ah," the rolling trill,
the soothing "ess."
- 說的倒是
- 我太愛意大利語了
-That's true.
-l love it.
行了 讓我教你一個詞吧
All right, let me teach you a word.
良藥
Therapist.
- 不會吧
- 很好 你得學點幽默感
-Come on.
-Good. You gotta learn humor.
- 才不是
- 來 乾杯
-lt's not.
-Come on. Cheers.
- 星期二五點我們繼續?
- 好的
-Shall we continue Tuesday at 5?
-Yes.
- 再來一瓶良藥?
- 當然
-With another bottle of the therapy?
-Of course.
- 你學得很快 麗茲
- 謝謝
-You're doing very well, Liz.
-Thank you.
當你學會些新東西時...
And you must be very polite
with yourself...
...你肯定很自豪
...when you learn something new.
是的 謝謝 我同意你的說法
Yes. Grazie, I agree.
但你的英語水準...
你跟我說這些不太合理吧?
But your English-- How are you
even talking to me like this right now?
應該是你教我多過我教你的
I think you're gonna teach me
more than I teach you.
你意大利語不錯 很好了
You have good Italian. Very good.
好吧
All right.
我孤身一人
I am alone.
我感到很愧疚
都到羅馬三周了...
I feel so guilty.
I've been in Rome for three weeks...
...我所做的一切只是
學會一點意大利語和吃東西
...all l've done is learn
a few ltalian words and eat.
你感到愧疚是因為你是美國人
You feel guilty
because you're American.
你們不懂得如何讓自己快樂
You don't know
how to enjoy yourself.
- 你說什麼?
- 是真的
-l beg your pardon?
-lt's true.
美國人知道怎麼娛樂
卻不知道什麼是快樂
Americans know entertainment,
but don't know pleasure.
這位是盧卡.斯帕蓋蒂
This is Luca Spaghetti, by the way,
you know.
你叫盧卡 斯帕蓋蒂(意大利麵)?
Your name is Luca Spaghetti?
是的 那是我家族的姓氏
Yes, that's what our family is called.
意大利麵是我們發明的
我是很認真的 聽我說
We invented it.
I'm serious. Listen to me.
你想知道問題的癥結所在麼? 美國人
You want to know your problem?
Americans.
你們工作太努力了
你們精疲力竭
You work too hard.
You get burned out.
當你們回到家 整個週末...
Then you come home
and spend the whole weekend...
...居然是穿著睡衣看一天的電視
...in your pajamas in front of the TV.
好像是這樣 差不多
That's not far off, actually.
但你們不知道什麼是快樂
還需要別人告訴你們才行
But you don't know pleasure.
You have to be told you've earned it.
有個廣告說
"是享受Miller(美樂啤酒)的時間了"
You see a commercial that says,
"It's Miller time"...
...然後你就想
"沒錯 我現在就去買一打"
...and you say, "That's right.
Now I will go to buy a six-pack."
然後就一口氣全喝了
第二天早上醒來 感覺糟透了
And drink the whole thing and wake up
the next morning and you feel terrible.
意大利人就不需要別人提醒
But an ltalian doesn't need
to be told.
有個意大利人被告知說
"你需要休息一下"...
He walks by a sign that says,
"you deserve a break today"...
...然後他說 "哦 這我知道...
...and he says, "Yeah, l know.
...所以我才計劃中午到你家...
That's why I'm planning on
taking a break at noon...
...休息一下 跟你妻子睡一覺"
...to go over to your house
and sleep with your wife."
我們稱之為 "dolcee far nirentee"
We call it "dolce far niente."
意思是...
It means...
...無所事事的快樂
意大利人是這方面的專家
...the sweetness of doing nothing.
We are masters of it.
他說沒錯 他說...
He's right. He says...
...你不能這樣學意大利語
...you can't learn ltalian like this.
你不僅要用嘴說 還要用手
You don't speak the language just with
your mouth, speak it with your hands.
像這樣?
Like this?
好啦 這是大聲嚷嚷
Okay. ls yelling.
"這菜太美味了"
'THAT MEAL WAS EXCELLENT'
"得了吧你"
'SUCK IT'
這些真讓人眼花繚亂
All this gives me a stomachache.
"去你媽的"
'SCREW YOU'
- 那好像是我鄰居羅蘭索
- 非常迷人(諷刺口吻)
-l think that's my neighbor Lorenzo.
-Charming.
另一種 "去你媽的"
ANOTHER WAY
TO SAY 'SCREW YOU'
好了 開始點菜吧 我要...
So anyway, to start off l'd say....
抱歉
Excuse me.
過來一下
Come here.
都要六人份量...
For the table...
...一大盤猶式洋薊
...a big platter
of artichoke alla giudia...
...意式熏火腿配甜瓜...
...prosciutto with melon...
...意式奶酪燴茄子
...and eggplant
with ricotta affumicata.
乾酪沙司意大利麵...
Then spaghetti alla carbonara...
...兔肉沙司意式粗麵...
...pappardelle with ragu of rabbit...
...意式寬麵配蛤蜊
...and linguini with clams.
羅馬牛肚...
Then tripe alla romana...
...還有意式煎小牛肉火腿卷
...and saltimbocca.
以及兩升岡扎諾葡萄酒
And two more liters
of the vino sfuso from Genzano.
謝謝
Thank you.
你辦到了 真棒
You did it. Yes.
麗茲.吉爾伯特  你現在是羅馬女人了
Liz Gilbert,
you are a Roman woman now.
僅僅是名譽頭銜而已
No, only honorary.
那才是真正的羅馬女人
That is a real Roman woman.
和跨種族的朋友一起
Yeah, with a lot
of international friends.
要是我就一口咬了
That one, I'd bite.
也許你和羅馬有不同的詞
Maybe you and Rome
just have different words.
- 不同的詞?
- 是的
-Different words?
-Yeah.
如果你認真想想
每個城市都有其獨特的詞
Yeah. lt's like each city has a word,
if you really think about it.
就像倫敦的詞是什麼?
Like, what is the word for London?
- 我說是 "窒息"
- 這我同意
-l would say "stuffy."
-l would agree with that.
- 斯德哥爾摩的呢?
- 開什麼玩笑 當然是 "舒適"
-What's the word for Stockholm?
-Are you kidding? "Conform."
紐約呢?
And New York?
"慾望" 或者 "煤煙"
"Ambition" or "soot."
那羅馬的詞是什麼?
What's the word for Rome?
這有點難
It's kind of difficult to think about.
這問題不錯
It's classic.
"性感"
"Sex."
顯然
Of course.
那你的詞呢 麗茲
我很好奇 我想不出來
So, what's your word, Liz?
I'm curious. l can't figure it out.
這個嘛...
Well....
可能是...
It might be....
以 "女兒"開始
我做得挺好 之後是...
It started as "daughter."
I was good at that. And then...
..."妻子" 不怎麼樣
..."wife." Not so good.
"女友"
"Girlfriend."
也不怎麼樣
Not so good.
還有 "作家"
My word's "writer."
那些都是你曾做過的
但不代表你是個什麼樣的人 對吧?
Yeah, but that's what you do.
That isn't who you are, no?
或許你是個在尋找自己詞的女人
Maybe you're a woman
in search of her word.
蘇菲 我是麗茲 我們去那不勒斯吧
或許我的詞就是"披薩"
Hey, Sofi, it's Liz. Let's go to Naples.
Maybe my word is "pizza."
聽著 女士 雖然我只有7歲
但是我看得出來你腦袋有問題...
Listen, lady, I am only 7, but l
can tell you're a complete moron...
...因為我是那不勒斯人
...because I am from Naples.
我喜歡這地方
但喬凡尼說來這裏得提高警惕
I love this place,
but Giovanni said to watch out.
他堂兄在這裏被搶了
還是在博物館裏
His cousin got mugged here
in a museum.
- 當真?
- 真的 要當心騎摩托車的
-Are you serious?
-Watch out for the scooter. Yeah.
我戀愛了 我愛上披薩了
I'm in love. l'm having
a relationship with my pizza.
你好像跟你的披薩分手了 怎麼了?
You look like you're breaking up
with the pizza. What's the matter?
我不能吃
I can't.
你不能吃是什麼意思?
這是那不勒斯的披薩
What do you mean, you can't?
This is pizza in Napoli.
享受這披薩是你應盡的義務
It is your moral imperative
to eat that pizza.
我也想吃 但我長胖了大概10磅
I want to,
but I've gained, like, 10 pounds.
我是說 我在這有...
I mean, l've got this....
就這位置 那叫什麼? 怎麼說的?
Right here. What's it called?
What's the word?
游泳圈
A muffin top.
我也有
I have one too.
5分鐘前我鬆開紐扣看著它
I unbuttoned my jeans
five minutes ago just looking at this.
我問你
Let me ask you a question.
這麼多年來 每當你在這麼多的男人面前脫衣服...
In all the years you've ever
undressed in front of a gentleman....
- 沒有很多男人
- 好吧 那...
-Hasn't been that many.
-All right, well...
他有要你離開嗎?
...has he ever asked you to leave?
- 他自己有離開? 走掉?
- 沒有
-Has he ever walked out? Left?
-No.
因為他不介意
Because he doesn't care.
他和一個裸女共處一室 他中獎了
He's in a room with a naked girl.
He's won the lottery.
我已厭倦了"控制食量" 還要在早晨醒來...
I'm so tired of saying no
and then waking up in the morning...
...回想昨日吃過的每樣東西
...and recalling every single thing
I ate the day before.
計算攝入的卡路里以便準確得知...
Counting every calorie
so l know exactly...
...究竟有多少自我厭惡感被帶進了浴室
...how much self-loathing
to take into the shower.
我討厭這樣
I'm going for it.
我不想變成胖子 我只是把內疚感拋之腦後
I have no interest in being obese.
I'm just through with the guilt.
我要做的 就是把這比薩餅搞定...
This is what l'm gonna do.
I'm gonna finish this pizza...
...然後我們去看足球比賽
...and then we're gonna go
watch the soccer game.
...到了明天再一起出外
And tomorrow we're gonna go
on a little date...
...給自己買幾件更大號的牛仔褲
...and buy ourselves
some bigger jeans.
喬凡尼喜歡游泳圈
Giovanni likes a muffin.
真乖
Attagirl.
他在說"你是為誰效力的?"
He's saying,
"For whom are you playing?"
為誰
Per chi, for whom.
拉 拉 我在用力塞進去
Pull, pull. l'm sucking it in.
給它來點瑞典式蠻力
Put some Swedish muscle into this.
你覺得這也發生在蘇菲亞·羅蘭(義大利電影女演員)身上嗎?
You think this happened
to Sophia Loren?
就是這樣 差不多了
There it goes. Almost got it.
加油 加油 你都沒在用力
Go, go, go. You're not trying.
快成功了 快成功了 我做到了
I've almost got it. l've almost got it.
I did it.
真漂亮 你該買下來
Oh, that's beautiful.
You should get it.
為誰而買?
For whom?
為你自己 麗茲 就為你自己
For you, Liz. Just for you.
不了 我買大號褲子就好
No, I'm happy just
with my big lady pants.
今天感謝你 還有為我騰出座位
Thanks for the day.
And the leg room.
那很有意思
It was fun.
我們要去吃東西 要來嗎?
We're gonna go for food.
Wanna come?
不了
No. No, l'm good.
無所事事的快樂
The sweetness of doing nothing.
求你 求你從地板上起來
Please. Please get off the floor.
能不能請你...? 可以上來這嗎?
Will you please just...?
Will you come up here?
我們彼此都知道這段關係被搞砸了...
What if we just acknowledge that
we have a screwed-up relationship...
但無論如何 我們依然堅持到底
你覺得這樣如何?
...and we stick it out anyway?
我們承認彼此間有很多爭吵...
We accept that we fight a lot...
...幾乎不再做愛...
...and we hardly have sex anymore...
...但彼此都不希望失去了對方
...but that we don't wanna
live without each other.
雖然我倆共同生活是如此...
And that way we can spend
our lives together...
...痛苦...
...miserable...
...但依然樂於彼此間沒走向分離
...but happy not to be apart.
親愛的大衛:
Dear David:
有好一段日子沒聯繫了...
We haven't had any communication
in a while...
...那給了我時間思考
...and it's given me time
I needed to think.
還記得你說過為了彼此的快樂...
Remember when you said we should
live with each other and be unhappy...
...我們要為對方不快樂的活著?
...so we could be happy?
把那想成是我對你的愛之宣言吧...
Consider it a testimony
to how much I love you...
...我花了長時間試圖實現那宣言...
...that I spent so long
pouring myself into that offer...
...努力希望能成功
...trying to make it work.
但在某天 我被朋友帶到那神奇的地方
But a friend took me to the most
amazing place the other day.
它名叫奧古斯都堡
It's called the Augusteum.
奧大維.奧古斯建造了它
以作為自己的存世之作
Octavian Augustus built it
to house his remains.
當外族入侵來到 他們把它跟
其他東西一樣當廢物毀掉了
When the barbarians came, they
trashed it along with everything else.
羅馬史上首位偉大的君主奧古斯...
The great Augustus,
Rome's first true great emperor...
...他又怎能想像到羅馬...
...how could he have imagined
that Rome...
...他的心能與之顧及到的整個世界
會成為斷壁殘垣?
...the whole world, as far as he was
concerned, would be in ruins?
在黑暗的中世紀
有人來到這把君主的骨灰偷走了
During the Dark Ages, someone came
in here and stole the emperor's ashes.
在12世紀 它成了一軍事堡壘...
In the 12th century,
it became a fortress...
...然後是鬥牛場
...then a bullring.
之後他們就把這變成了儲存木柴的地方
They stored fireworks in here
after that.
如今 它是無家可歸者的澡堂...
Nowadays, it's a bathroom
for the homeless...
...你要小心別踩空
...so you better watch your step
going down.
那裏是羅馬城最安靜和最孤獨的地方之一
It's one of the quietest
and loneliest places in Rome.
城市已經在它周圍成長了幾個世紀
The city has grown up
around it over centuries.
它就如一珍貴的傷口...
It feels like a precious wound...
就如破碎的心
那傷痛之深刻以致你無法釋懷
...like a heartbreak you won't let go of
because it hurts too good.
我就喜歡凌亂
I like it messy.
我們都希望一切如舊 大衛
We all want things
to stay the same, David.
我猜你的前任肯定是個天使 對吧?
I guess the guy before me
must've been some angel, huh?
在痛苦中過著安定的生活...
Settle for living in misery...
...因為我們害怕改變
害怕事物會變得支離破碎
...because we're afraid of change,
of things crumbling to ruins.
我環看這四周 處在一團混亂中....
Then I looked around in this place,
at the chaos it's endured...
...它忍受著自身被(環境)改變
被焚燒 被掠奪...
...the way it's been adapted,
burned, pillaged...
...然後找到重塑自己的方式
(那一刻)我就釋然了
...then found a way to build itself
back up again, and I was reassured.
或許我的人生沒如此複雜混亂
世界就是這個樣子而已...
Maybe my life hasn't been so chaotic.
It's just the world that is...
...需要注意的是
它正觸及(我人生的)各方面
...and the only real trap
is getting attached to any of it.
毀滅是一份恩賜
Ruin is a gift.
毀滅是通往改變的道路
Ruin is the road to transformation.
嗨
Hey.
可以走了嗎?
You ready?
可以
Yeah.
儘管在這座永恆的城市
奧古斯都堡依然向我展示了...
Even in this eternal city,
the Augusteum showed me...
...我們應該為永無休止的改變做好準備
...that we must always be prepared
for endless waves of transformation.
比起綁在一起 我們都應該過得更好...
Both of us deserve better
than staying together...
...不要害怕分開帶來的傷害
...because we're afraid
we'll be destroyed if we don't.
- 我母親正在填塞料
- 硬麵包 胡桃 拿那些過來
My mother's stuffing.
Stale bread, walnuts, got those.
能多拿點馬鈴薯給我嗎?
Will you get me
some more potatoes?
我總是要幫你拿多點馬鈴薯
Oh, l'm always getting you
more potatoes.
那是我的夢想 過上地道的美式感恩節
It's my dream,
a real American Thanksgiving.
那是向麗茲送行的最好方式
The perfect way to say goodbye
to our Liz.
那麼...
So...
- 你要在這周離開嗎?
- 是的
- ...you leave this week, huh?
-Yes.
要去哪 伊朗?
And where are you going? lran?
印度
India.
麗茲今晚為我們帶來了真實的美國風
Liz is making us
an American meal tonight.
- 你還沒結婚吧?
- 沒有
-You are not married, yeah?
-No.
你朋友是怎麼了? 她是拉拉嗎?
What's wrong with your friend,
is she a lesbian?
不 媽媽 她不是拉拉
還有 她聽得懂意大利語
No, Mama, she's not a lesbian.
And she understands ltalian.
她在世界的另一邊...
How's she going to find
another husband and start a family...
...怎麼可能找到丈夫與之共築愛巢呢?
...when she's on the other side
of the world?
如果有男人說"我願以一年時間作交換
用來結識好朋友..."
If a man said, "l'm going to travel for
a year and meet wonderful people...."
她又不是男人
But she's not a man.
對女人來說 要讓自己有選擇的權利是很困難的
It's more difficult for a woman to feel
that she has the right to make choices.
- 那需要很大勇氣
- 正是
-lt takes a lot of courage.
-Exactly.
你說是勇氣 我認為是愚蠢
You call it courage, I call it stupidity.
媽 夠了
Mama, enough.
我知道有很多人會同意你的看法
I know a number of people
who would agree with you.
盧卡?
Luca?
火雞什麼時候能好?
What time will the turkey be ready?
火雞....
The turkey....
我還沒解凍
I haven't defrosted it yet.
該死
Oh, shit.
只要你做這件事 你竟然搞砸了
You only had one thing to do
and you screwed it up.
我分神了 常有的事
I was distracted! It can happen!
好吃的東西太多
Too much good food!
女人太多
Too many women!
然後我就忘了
And l forgot!
我們在吃之前 各位...
Now, before we eat, everyone...
...感恩節 讓我們來做感恩禱告
...it is Thanksgiving,
so let us give thanks.
- 來吧 手拉手
- 好的
-Yeah. Come on, join hands.
-Okay.
就說我們...
So we just say what we....
我們今晚要感謝上帝
蘇菲 要不你先來?
What we thank God for tonight.
Sofi, why don't you start?
我感謝你 麗茲...
I am grateful for you, Liz...
...你幫我熱愛生活...
...for helping me appreciate life...
....以及這種熱愛帶來的一切...
...with all that comes with it...
...游泳圈和不開心的日子
...muffin tops and bad times.
對於喬凡尼...
And for Giovanni...
...感謝你讓我感受到了...
...for making me feel...
...愛與安全感
...loved and secure.
到朱利歐
And Giulio.
我對家庭表示感激
Me, l'm grateful for
my beautiful family.
我的妻子和兩個女兒
My two little daughters and my wife.
我感謝主和聖女...
I thank God and the Holy Virgin...
...為我們帶來如此特別的日子
...for this very, very special day.
如此美好的家庭...
And for this beautiful family...
...那讓今天的意義變得更重大
...that today is so much bigger.
非常重大
Very much bigger.
我感謝你帶來這種新的慶祝方式
I thank you all for this new custom
of celebration.
還有麗茲幫忙填塞料...
And Liz's stuffing...
...感謝主...
...and God...
...賜予我性感魅力
...for my sexiness.
你呢 羅費娜?
And you, Ruffina?
我感謝主...
I thank God for...
...為我帶來性感
...my sexiness.
繼續啊 喬凡尼
Go ahead. Giovanni.
我感謝主...
I thank God for...
...賜予我惶恐感...
...fear...
...因為這是首次...
...because for the first time...
...害怕坐在我旁的...
...l'm afraid the person next to me...
...將會是想離開的那一方
...will be the one who wants to leave.
麗茲?
Liz?
我感激所有這一切
Well, this all makes me so grateful.
看到你們這群快樂的人...
Seeing all you happy people...
...你們懂得互愛和互助
...who know how to love each other
and take care of each other.
我看著那讓我無比仰慕的出色女人...
I look at the amazing women l've met
who l admire so much...
...還有男人 照顧著自己的女人...
...and the great men,
taking care of their women...
...抱自己的孩子上床
...and putting their children to bed.
我感到開心...
I just feel happy...
...看見並參與到其中
...to see it and to be part of it.
我是世界上最幸運的女孩
I'm the luckiest girl in the world.
早餐真美味 對吧?
It's a good breakfast, huh?
我把這些帶到你房間去
I will take this to your room.
已經開始了
It has already started.
- 我睡著了
- 是的 遺憾啊
-l fell asleep.
-Yeah. Pity.
你可能是世上第一個在冥思中睡著的人
Probably the only person in the world
who ever fell asleep during meditation.
- 這路通往冥想園
- 精神導師在這嗎?
-This leads to the meditation garden.
-ls the guru here?
- 一直都在
- 我意思是 她真的在這裡嗎?
-She's always here.
-l know, but is she "here" here?
她現在紐約的修行地
She's at her ashram in New York.
但我是從紐約來這看她的
But l came from New York
to see her here.
聽著像是她玩的小把戲
Sounds like one of her little tricks.
冥想室
The meditation cave.
全天候開放 帶空調
It's open 24/7
and it's air-conditioned.
科瑞拉?
Corella?
- 這是麗茲.吉爾伯特
- 很高興見到你
-This is Liz Gilbert.
-Hi. Nice to meet you.
- 你在哪得到這胸牌的?
- 在書店有賣
-Where did you get that button?
-They sell them in the bookstore.
那正是我需要的 我不聆聽
That is exactly what I need. I need
something like that. l don't listen.
我一直都是這樣
我媽過去總是稱呼我"嘰嘰喳喳小姐"
I never have. My mom used to
call me Little Miss Chatty Cathy...
...因為我這人是話多嘮叨 我是嘮叨鬼
...because I just ramble.
I am a rambler.
我現在就在嘮叨了 對不起
I am rambling now. l'm sorry.
沉默是一種美妙的精神練習...
Silence is a wonderful
spiritual practice...
...如果科瑞拉能說話 她會告訴你
做起來比看著更有挑戰性
...but if Corella could speak, she'd tell
you it's more challenging than it looks.
- 你可能要過一段時間再試
- 好的
-Wait till you've been here for a while.
-Okay.
謝謝你 科瑞拉 我會轉告她的
Thank you, Corella.
I'll be sure to tell her.
- 她說什麼了?
- 不知道
-What did she say?
-No idea.
換上工作服 我要把你帶進seva(服務)
Change into your work clothes.
I'll take you to your seva.
那是印度語 意為"無私奉獻的工作"
It's a Hindu word
for "selfless devotional work."
- 每個留下來的人都必須做
- 好的 謝謝你
-lt's required of everyone who stays.
-Okay. Thank you.
世上還有比印度青少年更瘦小的同齡人嗎?
Is there anything in this world skinnier
than an lndian teenage boy?
- 我叫圖絲  - 麗茲
-l'm Tulsi.
-Liz.
你來自哪裏?
Where are you from?
隔壁村 我父母皈依精神導師很多年了
The next town. My parents have been
devotees of the guru for many years.
我們花很多時間在這
We spend a lot of time here.
可是...
But...
他們要把我嫁出去 這裏的傳統
...they are trying to marry me off.
That's the custom.
- 那不是你想要的?
- 才不 那糟透了
-That's not what you want?
-No way. lt sucks.
我想跟精神導師一樣 上大學修讀心理學
I want to study psychology, just as our
guru did when she attended college.
在這年紀 我選擇與主而不是與男孩一起
I prefer to be with God
than boys my age.
家裏沒人明白我大老遠跑來印度是為何
No one in my family understands
my coming all the way to India.
你曾否有過看著他們在想
"我待在這個家是幹什麼?"
Do you ever look at them and wonder,
"What am I doing in this family?"
那你可無法想像
You have no idea.
這古老的精神詩文內容包含了182篇詩文
The Guru Gita is an ancient text
1 82 verses long.
裏面說 巴瓦娣女神問濕婆神
或者叫上帝...
In it, the goddess Parvati
is asking Shiva, or God...
...(怎樣)實行的秘密
...for the secrets of fulfillment.
上帝說 那需要轉化的特質
It's said to have
transforming qualities.
我想冒昧地說一下...
I would just like to take a risk here
and say....
精神導師和我處得不太好
Me and Guru Gita,
we just do not get along.
- 你有什麼困難?
- 所有的一切
-What is it you have trouble with?
-Everything.
它如此冗長沉悶 我跟不上
It's long, it's tedious,
I can't keep up...
...然後它讓我對生活中所有事物
都抱有神經質般的焦慮...
...and l get these insane anxieties
about everything in my life...
...我已經找不到屬於自己的位置了
...and l've lost my place.
聽來像是起了很好的作用...
Sounds like it has a positive effect...
...能讓你在情感上和行為上有這麼強烈的反應
...if you're having such strong
emotions and physical reactions.
你繼續努力
You keep trying.
你結束婚姻的舉動真是讓人敬佩
It is most commendable
that you ended your marriage.
你現在是個自由快樂的人了
You seem like such a
happy, free person now.
我想前夫會說我自私
I think my ex-husband
would describe me as selfish.
你不該對自己生氣或失望
You mustn't be angry with yourself
or disappointed.
你不用為生孩子或結婚組建家庭而煩惱
You don't have to make children
or be married to have a family.
天 這裏的蚊子個頭真大...
Oh, man. They got mosquitoes
here big enough...
...直接就伏在上面 把雞給幹掉了
...to stand flat-footed
and screw a chicken.
- 我好崇拜你
- 麗茲 你見過...
-l love you.
-Liz, have you met...
- 來自德州的理查了嗎?
- 你好 來自德州的理查
-...Richard from Texas?
-Hello, Richard from Texas.
- 很高興見到你 食品雜貨小姐  - 食品雜貨?
-Nice to meet you, Groceries.
-Groceries?
- 是的
- 見到你之前我聽到你在吃東西
Yeah. Yeah, l heard you eating
before l saw you.
我從沒見過有人能一次吃那麼多
I never seen anybody
eat so much at one time.
你的確挺享受你的食物
You sure do enjoy your groceries.
要知道 今天很難熬
如果大家不介意的話
You know, it's been a rough day,
and if no one takes it personally...
...我另找地方能安靜地吃完這頓飯
...l'm going to take my large meal
someplace else to eat it in silence.
不用 留下吧 我吃完了
Oh, no, stay. I'm done.
看來你今天早上聊了些.
Looked like you were
working through some...
挺痛苦的話題
...pretty rough stuff this morning.
有關你前夫的?
Stuff with your ex-husband?
我有個前妻
I got an ex-wife.
她想我是把名字改成了"王八羔子"
She thinks l changed my name
to "Motherfucker."
我--
I--
我在羅馬待了些日子
剛來這兒時我感覺很好
I just spent some time in Rome
and l came here feeling so great.
現在我心底有種...
And now here l am, at the source...
...從未有過的隔絕
...and l feel more disconnected
than ever.
你為什麼來這裏?
Why'd you come here?
想在這裏找到安寧
I just want some peace.
安寧?
Peace?
要想到達城堡(意思想得到想要的一切)
食品雜貨小姐...
You wanna get
to the castle, Groceries...
...你必須游過護城河
(必須通過自身艱苦主動的努力)
...you got to swim the moat.
給你 我知道你能吃完的
Here, you can finish that.
I know you can.
好的
Okay.
簡單地清空雜念
Simply empty your mind.
呼吸
Breathe.
這年我都幹什麼了?
What am l going to do
when this year is over?
我將要到哪去住?
Where am I going to live?
芝加哥吧 也許
Well, maybe Chicago.
對了 我可以建個冥想室
Oh, my God.
I could build a meditation room--
不 別想了 為何就這麼難?
No. Stop thinking.
Why is this so hard?
去你的 科瑞拉 她是怎樣做到的?
Screw you, Corella.
How the hell does she do this?
她就像那該死的德雷莎修女
She looks like
frigging Mother Teresa.
天呀 殺了我吧
Oh, my God, kill me.
- 今天誰泡在護城河裏了?
- 閉嘴
-Who's in the moat today?
-Shut up.
看來你被鱷魚纏上了
Sounds like you wrestled
some big-ass crocs.
要是你這麼聰明 幹嘛還待在這?
You know what? lf you're so goddamn
smart, what are you doing here?
你能來這已經是一個聰明的舉動
If you're here,
it makes you smart already.
- 你要談談嗎?
- 對著你不用 謝謝
-Do you wanna talk about what--?
-No, not to you. Thank you.
這裏只有我在 你遲早點都要說的
I'm the only one here. You're gonna
talk about it sooner or later.
我在那裏精神不能集中
I cannot focus in there.
腦裏想的都是怎樣裝潢冥想室
All I think about is my meditation room
and how to decorate.
你在跟我耍花樣嗎?
Are you shitting me?
你在跟我開玩笑嗎?
Are you kidding me?
冥想室存在於內心 食品雜貨小姐
還裝潢它
The meditation room is within,
Groceries. Decorate that.
你說話時總是喜歡闡明宗教立場的嗎?
Do you always talk
in bumper sticker?
是的 這裏還有一句
I do, and here's another one.
你必須像每天選擇衣服一樣...
You have to learn to select
your thoughts the way you select...
...選擇自己的思維
這是你可以培養出來的能力
...your clothes every day.
That's a power you can cultivate.
你過來這是為了掌控自己的生活
You wanna come here and control
your life so bad, work on the mind.
從意念著手 那才是你該掌控的地方
That's the only thing
you should control.
如果不能掌控思維 你麻煩就大了
If you can't master your thoughts,
you're in trouble.
我在嘗試中
I am trying.
這正是問題所在 別嘗試了 投降吧
Yeah, hello, that's the damn problem.
Stop trying. Surrender.
就到院子裏坐著 停止一切想法...
Go out into the garden
and just sit there and still your mind...
...然後看會有什麼事發生
...and you watch what happens.
為何你就不能放手?
Why don't you just let it be?
有人說過你像詹姆斯泰勒(歌手)嗎?
Has anyone ever told you
you look like James Taylor?
每天都有
Every day.
天 他還真像
God, he really does.
我父母一直是那樣
My prayers were always the same.
"神啊 求求你 向我敞開心扉 給我神啟"
"Please, God, please.
Open my heart, send me a sign...
因為我們都知道我不是屋裏最鋒利的工具
(不是最聰穎 最有神性的人)
...because we both know
I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed."
看看你 神遊到加爾各答去了
(印度東北部港口城市)
Look at you,
floating through Calcutta.
看來你有了次很棒的冥想
Looks like you had
a great meditation.
我也許患上了瘧疾
I probably have malaria now.
痛楚會消失的
The bites will go away.
最終 所有一切都會消失
Eventually everything goes away.
祈求神啟 你之前做過嗎 食品雜貨小姐?
You ever done that, Groceries?
Begged for a sign?
這曖昧的意蘊聽著怪熟悉的
That sounds vaguely familiar.
小心所許的願 有可能會成真的
Be careful what you wish for.
You just might get it.
你沒問題吧?
What is your problem?
是不是錯愛了某人什麼的?
Did you fall in love
with the wrong woman or something?
打擾了 吉爾伯特小姐
Excuse me, Miss Gilbert.
你有電話
You have a phone call.
精神導師對你還好嗎?
How's the Guru Gita treating you?
不錯 你會喜歡上她的
Fine. You'd like her.
收到郵件了嗎?
Did you get my e-mail?
收到了 抱歉不能早點給你電話
Yeah. l'm sorry l didn't call sooner.
為什麼?
Why didn't you?
因為如果我不回電...
Because if l didn't respond...
...我們之間還存在溝通解決問題的可能
我依然還有希望
...we were still having a conversation.
I was still in it.
抱歉 只是我們的時機不對
I'm sorry. We were just bad timing.
我只想事情變得簡單
那樣一來我倆的關係就會好好的
I just wanted things to be easy.
We were good when things were easy.
不是說我現在不想要"簡單"點
只是不想逼得自己太"緊"
It's not that I need "easy" right now.
I just can't have "so hard."
聽起來你過得很好
Well, you sound good.
變堅強了
Stronger.
你也是
So do you.
我可是名演員 麗茲
Yeah, well, l'm an actor, Liz.
我得到了個角色
I got a part.
不是百老匯的 但也很不錯
It's off-Broadway,
but it's pretty cool.
我為你感到高興
I'm happy for you.
好了
All right.
那麼 日後再見吧
Well, l'll see you around, kid.
你好啊
Check you out.
從沒看過你如此聚精會神
I have never seen you so focused.
你要來瓶"大拇指"
(印度知名可樂品牌 可口可樂公司出品)
You need a Thums Up.
不 嘴唇別碰到瓶子
No, no. No lips on the bottle.
"除己之外 別碰任何東西"
印度第一準則
First rule in lndia is never
touch anything but yourself.
天 這口感 比可口可樂甜了5倍
Oh, good God. That's, like,
five times sweeter than Coke.
我想這裏面或加了甲基苯丙胺
I think it might have
methamphetamines in it.
希望不是吧
We can only hope.
我知道你感覺糟透了
I know you feel awful.
但你的生活正在發生變化
But your life's changing.
那不是壞事
That's not a bad thing.
你現又正處在極佳的地方
臣服在神的恩賜下
And you're in the perfect place for it.
Surrounded by grace.
我本以為跟他的事結束了 但是...
I thought I was over him, but...
...我愛他
...l love him.
有什麼大不了
Big deal.
- 就是說你愛上了某人
- 我真的很想他
-So you fell in love with someone.
-l really miss him.
那就去想吧
So miss him.
每次想他時就給他送去點愛與光明
然後再把它們放下
Send him some light and love every
time you think of him, then drop it.
如果能清空存於你腦海中...
You know, if you could clear out
all that space in your mind...
...用來迷戀這傢伙的...
...that you're using
to obsess over this guy...
...以及你那失敗婚姻的那些空間
你就能在門前騰出位置
...and your failed marriage,
you'd have a vacuum with a doorway.
知道茫茫宇宙能通過那門來幹什麼嗎?
(這裏的宇宙指人類無限的思維空間)
And you know what the universe
would do with that doorway?
上帝會由此處衝入
Rush in. God would rush in.
為你注滿你沒奢望過的大量的愛
Fill you with more love
than you ever dreamed of. Man.
食品雜貨小姐
Groceries.
我想將來的某一天
你會擁有能容下整個世界的愛
I think you have the capacity someday
to love the whole world.
那邊在賣什麼?
What do they sell over there?
象鼻神 能為你掃清一切障礙
Ganesh. Remover of obstacles.
我得需要很多這個
I'm gonna need a lot of these.
說到大象 現正有一厲害角色來了這裏
Speaking of elephants, there's a rogue
elephant on the loose in the area.
他正在做巡演
He was with carnival.
人們都說它高不可測
They say he is very,
very unpredictable and volatile.
那只會讓她對其更著迷
That just makes him more attractive
to her.
你怎麼會這麼有才?
我想當中肯定經歷了艱辛吧
How'd you get to be so smart?
I'll bet it was the hard way.
別轉話題
Don't change the subject.
天 什麼時候能跳過這些悲情的調子?
Well, when is this grieving phase
going to pass?
你想要個確切的日子嗎?
You want a day on a calendar
you can circle?
- 你能給我嗎?
- 不 你得去努力
-Can you give me one?
-No. You got to do the work.
冥思 去做seva(服務)...
Meditate and go to seva...
...最重要的是每天早上把屁股坐到坐墊上...
...and most important, get your butt
down to the Geet every morning...
...然後 事情自然會起變化
...and something'll change.
我不能達到精神導師的境界
找到那種虔誠與奉獻的感覺
I just cannot get through the Guru Gita.
I can't find that feeling of devotion.
虔誠在於愛 找個你想奉獻的人或事
Okay. Devotion's love. Pick somebody
or something you wanna devote it to.
不一定要是精神導師 對她來說 那都一樣
It doesn't have to be the guru.
It's all the same to her.
跟你自己有關
This is about you.
能否跟你說點事 食品雜貨小姐?
你有很嚴重的控制情結
Can l tell you something, Groceries?
You got some serious control issues.
那麼明顯呀?
Is it obvious?
好了 理查 從我腦海裏出來吧
All right, Richard,
get out from inside my head now.
把門關上
Shut the door.
- 那就是他?
- 那就是他
-That's him?
-That's him.
- 他很醜
- 才不 他很可愛
-He's hideous.
-No, he's not. He's cute.
他是射手座
He's a Sagittarius.
他在德里進修計算機編程
He studies computer programming
in Delhi.
成績很好
He has very good grades.
家裏也很富有
And his family is very, very wealthy.
他肯定是既自負又獨裁的人
He will be very conceited
and dictatorial.
我的人生就終結在17歲了
My life is over at 1 7.
圖絲
Tulsi.
女士們 先生們 歡迎來到舞池...
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the dance floor...
...現在有請麗茲和史蒂芬為各位
開始第一支舞
...for their very first couples dance,
Liz and Stephen.
我的朋友們
My people.
- 準備好了嗎?
- 準備好了
-Are you ready?
-l'm ready.
- 你看起來真漂亮
- 謝謝你
-You look beautiful.
-Thank you.
我跟一位辣妹結婚了
I married a hottie.
- 這是什麼呀? 不是我們的曲子
- 不 確實不是
-What is that? That's not our song.
-No, it is not.
親愛的 這不是我們的曲子呀
Baby, that's not our song.
- 肯定不是
- 大家都在看著我們呢
-Definitely not.
-Everybody's looking at us.
沒關係 我去跟那個人說 沒事的
It's okay. I'm gonna go talk to the guy.
It's gonna be fine.
- 我跟你說了我搞得定
- 你就是這麼搞定的啊?
-l told you l'd get it.
-This is taking care of it?
我欠你一份結婚禮物
因為不知道送什麼好
I owe you a wedding gift.
I didn't know what was appropriate.
我想跟你說我已經...
I wanted to tell you l've been...
...打算把我的印度經典"古魯梵歌"
獻給你了
...dedicating my Guru Gita to you.
想像你幸福的樣子
讓我領悟到梵歌的意義
Imagining you happy
is what got me through it.
我幸福的時候...
What did it look like...
...是什麼樣子?
...when I was happy?
我想像著你和瑞修...
I imagine you and Rijul...
...微笑著看著彼此...
...smiling and looking
at each other...
...眼神充滿愛和仁慈
...with love and kindness.
感覺十分真實
It seemed very real.
真的謝謝你 麗茲
Thank you so much, Liz.
我也會因此相信一切都會美好
That helps me to believe it as well.
在想你自己的婚禮嗎?
Thinking about your own wedding?
嗯 我也是
Yeah, me too.
婚禮最有意思的地方就在於
最後總會想到自己
The funny thing about weddings,
you end up thinking about yourself.
你給自己辦了一個盛大的舞會嗎?
那種大大軟軟的白色婚紗?
Did you throw yourself a big shindig?
Big, white, floppy dress?
是的 全都是我安排的
誰也沒強迫我做什麼
Yep. l arranged it all.
Nobody forced me into anything.
嗯 而你現在卻不能原諒自己
Yeah. And now
you can't forgive yourself.
說實話 我是在等他來原諒我
Honestly, I'm waiting for him
to forgive me.
讓我釋然
To release me.
等他原諒你就是浪費時間
浪費時間就是浪費生命 食品雜貨小姐
Waiting for him to forgive you
is a damn waste of time, Groceries.
原諒你自己吧
Forgive yourself.
不是那麼簡單的
It's not that easy.
是啊
Yeah.
晚安 理查
Good night, Richard.
- 跟我來吧
- 我累了
-Follow me.
-l'm tired.
趕緊過來
Get your butt up here.
雖然不是個好故事...
It's not a pretty story...
...但是相當典型
...but it's pretty classic.
大量的酗酒 吸毒 還有無心的欺騙
Too much alcohol, too many drugs,
too much mindless cheating.
遺憾而已
Just regret.
傷逝成海 追悔莫及
Ocean of regret.
我失去了一切
I lost everything.
我的自尊 我的工作
My pride, my job.
我的家庭
My family.
我失去了我的家人
I lost my family.
有一天下班之後 我在酒吧駐足
喝得爛醉
One day after work, l stopped off
at a bar and I got shitfaced.
那時的我和你很像
I was a lot like you, you know.
我只是... 我不知道
我想太多 我感覺太....
I was just-- I don't know.
I thought too much, I felt too....
我希望自己是麻木的
I wanted to feel nothing.
我本來可以叫輛出租車 但沒有
I should've called a cab, but I didn't.
我鑽進車裏 開回家
I just got in my car
and l drove home.
我的兒子
My little boy....
那時候他才8歲 他在...
He was 8 years old at the time.
He was pl--
他在坐在車道上玩著汽車模型
等著他那失敗又...
He was sitting in the driveway with his
little Hot Wheels, waiting for his lost...
窮困的酒鬼老爸...
...drunk, miserable dad...
...回家跟他玩
...to come home and play with him.
我沒看見他
I didn't see him.
我沒看見 我只是把車開到車道上
卻沒看見我的兒子
I didn't. I just roared into that driveway
and l didn't see my little boy.
但他...不 他....
But he-- No, he....
他閃開了
He got out of the way.
當我在車道附近 他都知道要躲遠一點
He was used to getting out of the way
when I was around.
而我卻...卻...
And l-- You know, I don't--
什麼都不記得了
I don't know.
I don't remember a thing.
隔天我醒來 他們已經走了
Next day, l woke up
and they were gone.
我妻子從窗子看著發生的一切
My wife had been watching
what happened out the window.
她再也不....
She just wasn't gonna....
她再也不想過這樣的生活
She just wasn't gonna
do it anymore.
所以....
So....
他現在18歲了
He's 1 8 now.
他在上學 而且 特別聰明
He's in school and,
oh, God, he's so smart.
上帝啊 他那麼討人喜歡而且....
God, he's so funny and he's....
那麼窩心
He's so sweet.
我卻錯過這一切
I missed it all.
我錯過了...
I missed...
...兒子成長的過程 我也錯過了
...my son's growing up. Just missed it.
你了解嗎?
Okay?
來
Come here.
這事兒這麼辦
Here's the deal.
在你原諒自己之前 就先在這呆著
You're gonna stay here
till you forgive yourself.
聽見沒有?
You hear me?
其它一切事兒都自有安排
Everything else
will take care of itself.
你就是在這兒自我原諒的?
Is this where you forgave yourself?
我在盡力而為 伊莉莎白
I'm trying, Elizabeth.
我在盡力而為
I am trying.
嘿
Hey.
我敢說這就是
我們婚禮上本應演奏的曲子
I believe this is the song they were
supposed to play at our wedding.
我的確愛過你 史蒂芬
I did love you, Stephen.
我知道
I know.
但我還是很愛你
But l still love you.
那就愛我吧
So love me.
但我思念你
But l miss you.
那就思念吧
So miss me.
每當想起我的時候
就用愛和光芒來潤澤我...
Send me love and light
every time you think of me...
...再黯然熄滅
...then drop it.
不會永遠的
It won't last forever.
沒有永遠
Nothing does.
- 拜拜
- 再見 理查先生
-Bye-bye.
-Goodbye, Mr. Richard.
我們再會
I'll see you.
你要走了的話
每天誰還來給我當頭棒喝呢?
Now that you're going,
who is gonna kick my ass every day?
噢 直到雨季讓我不得不離開之前
我都盡量一直在這兒了 拜拜
Oh, l'd stay till a monsoon
swept me away if I could. Bye-bye.
但是你還得付賬單 還得蓋房子
But you've got bills to pay
and houses to build.
你就繼續做事 過日子 成麼?
You just keep doing the work
and move on with your life, will you?
你這人都要上飛機了
卻還在對我指手畫腳
The man is getting on a plane
and you're still bossing me.
你說的我都記下來了: 接著過日子
看到不順眼的去向真主禱告...
I've got your whole list: move on,
use mosquito repellent and....
我不知道 還有些別的事兒
我都寫下來
I don't know. There were some
other things. I wrote them down.
回德克薩斯去吧 理查
Go back to Texas, Richard.
這已經是我在這兒的極限了
Well, l ain't getting
any prettier standing here.
所以我準備走了
So l'm off.
嘿 食品雜貨小姐
Hey, Groceries.
再次相信愛情吧
Believe in love again.
麗茲 麗茲 我今天把標識摘下來了
Liz. Liz, l've just taken
my badge off today.
我做得真不賴啊
四個星期一聲不吭 真累啊
I've done so well.
Four weeks of silence. lt was so dull.
但是這就像做了個整容
因為你的臉...
But it's like a facelift
because your face...
...那個 放鬆之後 你的喉嚨就會下垂
就是這麼回事兒
...you know, just relaxes and your
throat just drops down. It's a bargain.
我們有好多好多要補聊的
We've got so much to catch up on.
噢 沒事 對你有好處
你會受益良多的
Oh, golly. Good for you.
You will get so much out of that.
你的嗓音也會清澈無比
And your throat will look amazing
as well.
抱歉 伊莉莎白
Excuse me, Elizabeth.
他們要你在晚飯之後
到互助者辦公室報到...
They're asking you to report
to the seva office after dinner...
...如果你不介意的話
...if you don't mind.
我們準備讓你不再擦洗地板了
We're taking you off
the floor-scrubbing team.
明天會從世界各地
來50個左右的志願者...
There are about 50 devotees arriving
tomorrow from all over the world...
...隱居大概10天 我們打算讓你來
讓你當女主持
...for a 1 0-day retreat and we'd
like you to be the key hostess.
我們想請你就不要去參加冥想了
We ask that you don't take part
during the meditations.
我們需要你照顧來賓
確保每個人都賓至如歸
We need you to watch over the flock,
make sure everyone is all right.
我們管這職位的人叫小小乳酪奶油小姐
We call the person who does
this job Little Suzy Cream Cheese.
你得八面玲瓏 長袖善舞
還要一直微笑
You need to be social and bubbly
and smiling all the time.
女士...
Madam...
...我就是妳要找的人
...l'm your girl.
那就去找一下你的箱子吧
應該就在這兒附近的...
So just find your suitcase,
it should be here somewhere...
...然後就趕緊回房間
...and then head down the path
to your room.
這樣的話 印度大冒險的千言萬語
可以匯成一句話
So the holy truth of the whole
adventure here in India is in one line:
神與汝共鳴 神與汝同在
God dwells within you as you.
上帝對看那些善男信女們的...
God's not interested
in watching a performance...
...所作所為可不感興趣
...of how a spiritual person
looks and behaves.
安靜的女孩兒 悄無聲息地飄過...
The quiet girl who glides silently
through the place...
...還帶著空靈乖巧的微笑 那人是誰?
...with a gentle, ethereal smile,
who is that person?
那是聖瑪麗合唱團 不是我
That's lngrid Bergman
in The Bells of St. Mary's, not me.
神與我共鳴 神與我同在
God dwells within me as me.
被惡魔摧殘的孩子啊
Child tormented by demon.
看著像是在長牙
It looks like teething.
一樣
Same thing.
輪到你了
Your turn.
你好 科圖
Hello, Ketut.
見到你我很高興
I'm very happy to meet you.
你是個足跡遍及全世界的旅行者
You are a world traveler.
不 我大約一年前跑來看過你
No, I came to see you
about a year ago.
- 你從加利福尼亞來?
- 不 我從紐約來
-You girl from California?
-No, I girl from New York.
不記得了
Don't remember.
唔 你跟我說過應該再來巴里島的
Well, you told me
I should come back here to Bali.
你說我能幫你學英語...
You said I could help you
with your English...
...而且你也會跟我講你的見聞
...and you would teach me
the things that you know.
你給了我這個
You gave me this.
OK
Okay.
你 是你啊 我記得你
You. You. l remember you.
- 噢 那還好
- 你是那個從紐約來的悲哀的姑娘
-Oh, good.
-You sad girl from New York.
- 沒錯
- 你是麗茲啊 你回來了
-Yes.
-You Liss. You came back.
- 我回來了
- 是你 是你 是你
-l came back.
-You, you, you.
是我 是我 是我
Me, me, me.
我們好久不見
So long ago we meet.
上一次見你 你那麼憂心忡忡
那麼情緒低落
Last time, you have too much worry,
too much sorrow.
上次見你 你就像個
一臉愁苦的老太太
Last time,
you look like sad old woman.
現在你可真漂亮
Now you pretty.
- 為什麼變化會這麼大?
- 這個...
-Why so different?
-Well...
...因為很多事情啦 真的
...a lot of things, really.
不過我在羅馬待了四個月大吃大喝
But l was in Rome for four months,
just feeding myself...
...後來我去了印度的一座佛祠
...and then I went to live
at an ashram in lndia.
而今我們相聚了
Now, we put together.
沒錯 我就是為了這個來的
Exactly. That's why l'm here.
- 科圖很願意這樣
- 你貢獻了什麼給他?
-Ketut good for that.
-What'd you give him?
你還想讓我幫你學英語嗎?
Do you still want me to help you
with your English?
回頭再說英語的事兒 麗茲
English later, Liss.
首先 一個更好的主意
First, better idea.
這些都有多少年月了?
How old are these?
從祖父那一輩就有了
非常重要的法術
From grandfather.
Very important spells.
還有符咒和藥劑
Also mantras, cures.
一千多年了
Thousand years' worth.
我擁有的一切 我知道的一切
全在這兒了
All I have, all l know, right here.
能給我抄一份兒嗎?
You copy for me?
沒問題 我去城裏把這些拿...
Absolutely. l can go to town
and take these--
不 你不能拿走
No. You don't take.
你就抄在這兒 這樣更好 麗茲
You copy here, better, Liss.
我得打個盹兒 我年紀大了
I take a nap now. l very old.
你多大年紀了 科圖?
How old are you, Ketut?
一百零一歲了...
One hundred and one...
...或者也有可能是六十四歲
...or maybe 64.
不記得了
Don't remember.
我後半輩子就全花在這上了
This is gonna take me
the rest of my life.
他使你漂亮 為你找個愛人
你為他努力工作
He make you pretty, find you husband,
you work hard for him.
這跟我來這兒的原因正相反
That's exactly opposite
of why l'm here.
誰都得找個愛人啊
Everybody need husband.
能麻煩你給我拿點兒水嗎?
Would you mind getting me water?
我不去
No.
好吧 接著抄 我去拿水
Fine. Keep making copies.
I get water.
麗茲 巴里島人相信巴里島就是宇宙的中心
So, Liz, the Balinese believe
that Bali's the center of the universe.
而我們現在就在巴里島的中心
And here we are
in the center of Bali.
你有個臥室 有個釣魚池
You got the one bedroom,
got your fish pond.
你有自己的廟宇 可以冥想
You got your own meditation temple.
我跟你說啊 在炸彈事件之後
遊客是一天比一天少...
I tell you, since the bombing,
tourism's been way down...
...所以我可以開一個非常非常優惠
的價錢租給你這個地方
...so l can give you this place
at a very, very good price right now.
天堂
Paradise.
- 我就要它了
- 巴里島的人們明白...
-l'll take it.
-People in Bali understand...
...為了快樂常在 就要時時刻刻...
...in order to stay happy,
must always know where you are...
...領悟自己所處之境
...every moment.
這兒就是完美的平衡
天與地恰巧於此交匯
Right here is perfect balance.
Right at meeting of heaven and earth.
沒那麼多的高風亮節
沒那麼多的爾虞我詐
Not too much God,
not too much selfish.
否則的話 生活就太瘋狂了
Otherwise, life too crazy.
失去了平衡就失去了力量
You lose balance, you lose power.
早上起來 你做印度式的冥想
In morning,
you do meditation from India.
認真 要非常認真
Serious. Very serious.
白天呢 就要享受巴里島
In day, you enjoy Bali.
下午的話 就來找我
Then in afternoon, come see me.
一天將盡之時 你還要再次冥想
End of day, you do new meditation.
很簡單
Very simple.
靜坐 微笑
Sit in silence and smile.
我已經感覺到平衡了
I feel balanced already.
沒這麼簡單 麗茲
Not so easy, Liss.
臉上要笑 心裏更要笑
Smile with face. Smile with mind.
甚至連肝臟都要有微笑
Even smile in liver.
回頭見 小鱷魚
See you later, alligator.
噢 天啊
Oh, God.
- 你還好吧?
- 你瞎了嗎?
-Are you all right?
-Are you blind?
- 請讓我帶你去看醫生吧
- 我沒事兒 我只是...
-Please, let me take you to a doctor.
-l'm fine. l just--
看上去可不好
It looks bad.
很不好 麗茲
Very bad, Liss.
- 怎麼了?
- 這個白癡把我撞到了
-What happen?
-This idiot ran me off the road.
男人? 有錢嗎?
A man? He rich?
這很嚴重啊
This very hot.
- 你得看大夫
- 有你啊 你不就是個配藥方的人嗎
-You need healer.
-l have you. You're a medicine man.
- 不 你得去找懷恩
- 是的
-No. You need Wayan.
-Yeah.
這是加姆藥草 把這個喝了
比抗生素還管用
Jamu. Drink this.
Better than antibiotic.
她也讓你喝這個嗎?
She make you drink this?
- 我叫麗茲 你叫什麼?  - 圖蒂
- Tutti
-My name's Liz. What's yours?
-Tutti.
見到你很高興 圖蒂
Nice to meet you, Tutti.
- 你結婚了嗎?
- 沒有
-Are you married?
-No.
你確定嗎? 一次都沒結過?
You sure? Not even once?
好吧 有那麼一次...
Okay, well,
there was this one time...
...但是我發現我跟巴里島的人們說
我離過婚的時候 他們都大惑不解
...but l find when l tell people in Bali
that I'm divorced, it upsets them.
我也是 離婚了
Me too, divorce.
離婚讓你情緒低落 似被棄如敝屣
Divorce make you sad
and make you an outcast.
你很長時間沒有性生活了吧 親愛的
You have no sex
for a long time, baby.
我從你的膝蓋都能看得出來
I can tell by your knee.
軟骨非常乾燥
性愛分泌的激素能潤滑關節
The cartilage very dry.
Hormones from sex lubricate joint.
- 好吧
- 我為你禱告
-Okay.
-l pray for you.
我們是姐妹
We sisters.
亞美尼亞!
Armenia!
這是從巴西來的亞美尼亞
Armenia from Brazil.
亞美尼亞 這是從紐約來的麗茲
Armenia, this is Liz from New York.
- 嗨
- 見到你很高興 麗茲
-Hi.
-Lovely to meet you, Liz.
是不是該
用香蕉樹根來做頭髮保養了?
Time for a banana root
hair treatment?
- 沒錯兒 當然
- 能讓頭髮又長又有光澤
-Yes, of course.
-lt makes the hair long and lustrous.
就好像大概是1975年的影星雪兒
Like Cher circa 1 975.
你有漂亮的衣服嗎?
Do you have a nice dress?
一件而已
One.
今晚穿上 到謝克海灘來
Put it on tonight,
come to the Beach Shack.
我會為你引見一下大家
本地人和外來的都有
I'll introduce you to everyone.
The expats, the locals.
跳跳舞 你會喜歡的
You'll dance. You will love it.
噢 不 我覺得我的腿沒法跳舞
Oh, no, l don't think I can dance
with my leg like this.
當然沒問題 腿沒事兒
Of course you can. Leg no problem.
你看
You see.
現在你一定得來了
Now you have to come.
嗨 我想要杯加冰的龍舌蘭多加點檸檬
Hi. Could I get a tequila on the rocks
with a lot of lime, please?
馬上就來
Coming right up.
能請你喝一杯嗎?
Can l buy you a drink?
不了 多謝 我很好
No, thank you, I'm fine.
我...我差點兒讓你喪命
I-- l almost killed you.
我很抱歉 真的
I am sorry for that, really.
- 你好
- 嗨
-Hello.
-Hi.
我很抱歉 真的
I'm sorry, really.
對不起我笑了 但確實很不可思議
I'm sorry I'm laughing,
but it's amazing.
其實當時我就在聽這首歌
而磁帶彈出來了
I was actually listening to this song
in the car when the tape jumped.
我俯下身子弄好它
結果就撞到你了
And l leaned over to fix it
and l ran you off the road.
- 你讓他們放這首歌了嗎?
- 不不不 我把它們混成了一盤磁帶
-Did you tell them to play it?
-No, no, no. I make them mixtapes.
大部分是巴西音樂
Mostly Brazilian music.
但我也很喜歡菲爾.柯林斯
還有空中補給樂團
But l'm also very much into
Phil Collins and Air Supply.
你不該這麼大聲說話
You really shouldn't
say things like that out loud.
麗茲!
Liz!
- 嗨
- 看來你已經認識菲利培了
-Hi.
-Oh, I see you've already met Felipe.
哦 當然 兩個離婚的倒霉蛋兒
你們有很多共同語言
Oh, of course. Two sad divorces.
You have so much in common.
我給你提供一個最佳人選
I have the perfect man for you.
只需一點兒艷遇
每個來巴里島的人都會有一段的
Just a little love affair.
Everyone has a little love affair in Bali.
他很有魅力吧 伊恩
Isn't he charming? lan.
他像歌手斯汀吧
Doesn't he look like Sting?
噢 確實 我有一盤很棒的斯汀合輯
Oh, yeah.
I made a very good mixtape of Sting.
你該跟他一起跳支舞
You should dance with him.
就是你了 來吧 就是你了
Got you. Come on, l got you.
明天會疼的
That's gonna hurt tomorrow.
好吧 你猜怎麼著?
All right. You know what?
- 這樣吧 我們去游泳
- 不 我甚至沒帶我的...
-That is it. We are going swimming.
-No, I don't even have my-- l--
你不需要...你不需要...
You don't have your-- You don't--
你還真是一絲不掛啊
You're so naked.
嗯 我裸體了
Yeah, l'm naked.
亞美尼亞說每個人都該有次艷遇
Armenia says everyone
should have a love affair.
這就是巴里島 每個巴里島的人
都該有艷遇
This is Bali. Everyone should have
a love affair in Bali.
沒錯啦 但是...
Yeah, but--
噢 天啊 不 不 不
Oh, God. No, no, no.
- 艷遇最讚了 夥計
- 確實 我只是...
-Love affairs are awesome, dude.
-They are. l just--
15年前我會與你約會
I dated you 15 years ago.
6個月前我也會跟你約會
And l dated you six months ago.
所以我要走了
So l'm gonna go.
你不會-- 不會是真的--
你要走了
You're not-- You're really--
You're going.
不過你很可愛
But you're cute.
我覺得自己還挺帥的
I think I look good.
等一下
Wait a minute.
抱歉 給你
Oh, sorry. Here.
- 謝謝你
- 要不要送你一程?
-Thank you.
-Do you need a ride?
這樣的話我就不會再撞到你了
That way I won't run you over again.
你好
Hello.
- 現在幾點了?
- 凌晨5點
-What time is it?
-Five a.m.
你在派對上挺瘋的
Oh, you party hard.
好瘋狂
You really do.
謝謝你....
Thank you for....
- 送你回來?
- 對
-The ride?
-Yeah.
不用客氣 要不要幫你搬下單車?
You're very welcome.
Need help with the bicycle?
你留著吧
You keep it.
留著? 單車上有個籃子
Keep it? But it has a basket.
還有個鈴鐺呢
It also has a bell.
下午好 你還好嗎?
Good afternoon. How are you?
你在這幹嘛啊?
What are you doing here?
我給你帶來了懷恩著名的解酒方子
Well, l've brought you
Wayan's famous hangover cure...
你昨晚有點喝多了
...because you drank
a little bit too much last night.
就是這個 很好喝...
And here it is.
Very delicious, as you can see...
口感不錯的
...and very tasty.
你是不是習慣了
大搖大擺的跑進別人家裏?
Do you make it a habit of
walking into people's houses?
你是不是習慣了
開著大門呼呼大睡?
Do you make it a habit of
sleeping with your front door open?
有電話 稍等
It's a call. Moment.
- 親愛的 你還好嗎?
- 咖啡機壞了
-Hello, darling. How are you?
-Can't get the coffee machine to work.
我跟你說過一百次了 很簡單的
Okay. l've told you 50 times.
It's very easy.
更換濾網 倒入咖啡...
You change the filter,
you add the coffee...
再加點水就好了
你這樣還能考上大學啊?
...you add water and that's it.
How did you get into college?
- 我怎麼才能像你一樣?
- 我煮咖啡
-How do l make it like you?
-Listen, l've been making coffee...
有四十年了 所以你得沉住氣 懂嗎?
...darling, for 40 years, so you have
to be patient with yourself. All right?
好吧 你在幹嘛呢?
Okay. So, what's up with you?
- 沒什麼 就是不太方便說話
- 我靠 你跟女人在一起
-Nothing. l just can't talk right now.
-Holy shit. You're with a girl.
- 我得掛了
- 她是誰? 很辣嗎?
-l have to go.
-Who is she? ls she hot?
- 天哪 她很辣
- 爸 你要是掛了電話...
-Jesus, she's hot.
-Dad, if you hang up...
我就會再打過去 讓你在她面前尷尬
...l'll call back and embarrass you.
爸爸 別--
Dad, don't--
親愛的 你叫了那麼多次"親愛的"
That's a lot of "darlings," darling.
對 那是我親愛的兒子
Yeah. That darling was my son.
孩子們還小的時候
我就叫他們"親愛的"了
I've called all my children "darling"
since they were little.
看著寵物和孩子們
Then there was a moment that
between the pets and the children...
我有時候會分不清
所以我見誰都叫"親愛的"
...l was confused,
so l called everybody "darling."
好了 你得歇會兒了
Okay, you need to rest.
這是我的電話和地址
Here is my number and my address.
我會放在桌子上
你需要導遊的時候可以找我
I'm gonna leave it here on the table,
in case you need a tour guide.
導遊
A tour guide.
拜託把解酒藥喝了
你會感覺好很多的
And please, drink that up, because
it's gonna help you a big deal.
你現在看起來真的...
Because you really look....
- 很迷人?
- 很驚人
-Ravishing?
-Astonishing.
- 快走啦
- 好 記得要喝
-Go away. Please.
-Okay. Drink it up.
很管用的
It's gonna be helpful.
導遊先生
Hey, Mr. Tour Guide.
我們喝杯咖啡好嗎?
Can we start with a coffee?
好啊
Okay.
這是什麼啊?
What are these?
是紅毛丹果 可好吃了
These are rambutan.
They're delicious.
就像橙子和杏子的愛情結晶
要不要試試?
It's like an orange made love
to a plum. Would you like some?
你這樣說的話 就來點吧 謝謝
When you put it that way,
yes, thank you.
請問一下
Excuse me.
那是什麼?
What is that?
別 別
No, no, no.
這味道就跟臭腳似的
They taste like dirty feet.
- 真的?
- 臭腳丫味
-Really?
-Dirty feet.
這味道跟臭腳似的
They taste like feet.
小心 挺不錯啊 你去過多少地方?
Look out. Nice.
How many places have you visited?
我的護照上有46個印章
I have 46 stamps on my passport.
我的有49個
I happen to have 49 stamps
on my passport.
- 49個? 我就知道
-Forty-nine? I knew it.
-Yes.
- 知道什麼?
- 我就知道
-Knew what?
-l knew it.
親愛的 我們都是安特瓦信人
We are both antevasins, my dear.
那是什麼?
What is that?
安特瓦信人是....
Antevasin is....
中間人
It's an in-between.
住在邊境上
It is the one who lives
by the border...
他們放棄了舒適的家庭生活
...because they renounce
to the comfort of family life...
只為追尋神之啟示
...in order to seek "enlightment."
我喜歡你的用詞
I like your word.
我還喜歡你說"神之啟示"的語氣
And l like the way
you say "enlightment."
"神之啟示" 我是這樣說的
"Enlightment." I try.
你漏了個音節 不過我喜歡
You're missing a syllable,
but I like it.
很美吧?
It's beautiful, no?
是普拉.梅拉丁 意為"繁盛之寺"
It's Pura Melanting,
which means "Temple of Prosperity."
- 真美
- 是啊
-Beautiful.
-Yup.
- 去下一個景點吧?
- 好啊
-So next attraction of the tour?
-Yes.
- 巴里島美食
- 太好了 餓死我啦
-Food from Bali.
-Oh, good. l'm starving.
- 我們去哪呢?
- 鎮上最棒的餐館
-Where should we go?
-To the best restaurant in town.
- 那是當然
- 我的家
-Of course.
-My place.
真狡猾
Subtle.
你去巴里島之前一直住在巴西嗎?
Did you always live in Brazil
before you came to Bali?
沒有啦 住了20年而已
No, no. Only for 20 years.
然後我認識了我的太太
和她一起搬去了澳大利亞
Then l met my wife
and l moved with her to Australia.
她因為工作的緣故四處遊走
She traveled a lot
because of the job.
- 我就在家帶孩子
- 男女平等的好老公
-And I stayed home with the children.
-A good feminist husband.
對啊 可惜這不是她想要的
Yeah. Yeah. Didn't turn out to be
what she wanted, l'm afraid.
- 怎麼了?
-What happened?
孩子長大了
Well, the children were grown.
我做起珠寶進出口的生意
所以我想住哪都行
And l run an import-export jewelry
business, so I could live anywhere.
巴里島看起來是個
讓人走出離婚陰影的聖地
And Bali seemed like the perfect place
to recover from a divorce.
我就來了 來到這裏 就是這樣
And here l am. Here l am.
- 你呢?
- 沒你那麼悲啦
-And you?
-Well, far less tragic.
我們都不成熟 結婚太早 於是分開了
We were immature and really too
young to get married. We grew apart.
你們都很心碎
Hearts were broken.
是的
Yes.
那我們都一樣
Then it's the same.
這太完美啦
This is just perfect.
你也是
So are you.
知道你怎樣嗎 你是假瘦
You know what you are?
You're a falsa magra.
- 知不知道什麼意思?
- 什麼?
-You know what that is?
-What?
遠看苗條優雅
You are slender and elegant
in a distance...
近看卻圓潤豐腴
...but up close,
you are round and fleshy.
巴西人太可愛了
Thank God for Brazilians.
別這樣!
Stop that!
你是世界旅行者
You are a world traveler.
他見誰都這樣說
He says that to everyone.
已經賺到了錢
Already make your money.
你缺乏年輕人的勃勃雄心
You don't have young-man ambition.
- 他好厲害
- 你有三個小孩
-He's good.
-You have three children.
兩個啦 那是個老繭
Two. That's a callous.
你離婚了
And you have divorce.
很不好受
Very difficult.
你很愛她
You loved her very much.
你的傷還沒痊癒
You haven't healed that wound.
現在你不敢打開心扉
Now you are scared
to open your heart.
害怕再次受傷
You are afraid
hurt will happen to you again.
療傷的唯一關鍵
Only way to heal...
在於信任
...is to trust.
沒關係的 曾經心碎意味著你曾付出
This okay. To have broken heart
mean you have tried for something.
我的心 還會再碎一次嗎?
Is it going to be broken again?
麗茲 他是個好男人 你需要好男人
He a good man, Liz.
You need a good man.
謝謝
Thank you.
真的 科圖知道的
True. Ketut knows.
誰都說我需要個男人 聽的都煩了
I am so sick of people telling me
I need a man.
麗茲 你不需要男人
你需要王者
You don't need a man, Liz.
You need a champion.
- 放春假了吧?
- 快點啦 你們跟烏龜似的
-Some spring break, huh?
-Come on. You're moving like turtles.
他的熱情快要耗盡了
His enthusiasm is exhausting.
十歲時他送我去學校...
Try being dropped off at school
when you're 10...
吻別還要親嘴
...and having your father
kiss you on the mouth.
到現在還這樣
He still does it.
我知道在巴西這很平常
可我又不是在巴西長大的
I'm sure it's all normal in Brazil,
but I didn't grow up in Brazil.
我都被朋友們笑死了
Friends would tease
the crap out of me.
那你怎麼不叫他別這樣呢?
Why didn't you ask him to stop?
算了 一開始我說了 然後我意識到
No, I did at first,
but then l realized...
我放棄堅持 他就高興的很
...how happy it made the old guy
and l just gave in.
知道嗎 我奶奶比你們走得都快呢
You know what? My grandmother
hikes faster than you both...
可她早就去世了
...but she's already dead.
揍他 去揍他
Get him. Go get him.
不如你來背一會兒背包吧?
How about you carry the packs
for a while, eh?
過來這裏 你們看
Come here. Look at this.
很漂亮吧?
Is it nice?
寶貝
Baby.
我殿後了
Bringing up the rear.
- 你和她上床了嗎?
- 什麼意思?
-So have you slept with her yet?
-What was that?
你和她上床了嗎?
Have you slept with her yet?
你問得過分了
Crossing the line.
老爸 都十年了 是時候了
Dad, it's been 10 years. lt's time.
避開漂亮的女人
Stay away from
all the beautiful girls.
他們很危險的
They are dangerous.
- 一個星期太短了
- 對
-A week is too short.
-Yeah.
- 一個星期太短了
- 對
-A week is too short.
-Yup.
我幫你做了個合輯
Listen, l've made you a mixtape.
作為禮物送給你
And l give you a present. For you.
謝謝
Thank you.
我已經開始想你了
I'm missing you already.
再見 麗茲
Bye, Liz.
- 小心的
- 你也是
-Be safe.
-Same to you.
怎麼不親我了?
So don't I get a kiss?
不知道
I don't know.
- 我愛你 爸爸
- 我也愛你
-l love you, Dad.
-l love you too.
很傻 我知道
So stupid, I know.
他19歲了 有男子氣概了
He's 19 years old
and he's such a man.
很貼心
It's sweet.
你很貼心
You're sweet.
親愛的
Darling...
是時候了
...it's time.
- 麗茲  - 怎麼?
-Liz.
-What?
麗茲 過來 我得告訴你一些事
Liz. Come here.
I have to tell you something.
不 我真的要冥想了
No. I should really,
really be meditating.
去吧 去冥想
Go, go. Do it.
我已經兩個星期沒去見科圖了
You know, I have not been
to see Ketut in two weeks.
- 真的?
- 真的
-Really?
-Yes.
- 好的 去吧
- 好
-Okay. Go, go.
-Okay.
天哪 可是你比科圖可愛多了
Oh, gosh. But you are just
so much cuter than Ketut.
別 我得走了 我得走了
No, I have to go. I have to go.
為什麼?
Why?
你膀胱感染了
You have bladder infection.
通常是因為一段日子沒做愛
接著又性愛過度
Common after no sex,
then too much sexy time.
我們這兩星期來 一分鐘都沒分開過
We haven't even been apart
for a minute in two weeks.
你害怕了 是吧?
You're afraid now, right?
我懂
I understand.
你不想失去自我
You don't want to lose yourself.
愛情令人恐懼 危險重重
Love is scary, dangerous.
我曾經歷過
Happen to me.
我每天都在祈禱 丈夫卻對我不好
I pray every day,
but husband bad for me.
我要離開他
I have to get away from him.
他打我這兒
This from where he hit me...
用摩托頭盔打我
...with motorcycle helmet.
然後我的女兒
And then my daughter...
求我離開他
...she begged me to leave him.
對嗎 親愛的?
Is that right, honey?
我說 媽咪 我認為你應該離婚
I said, "I think you should
get a divorce, Mommy."
她說那話的時候才四歲
She was 4 years old
when she said it.
不要討厭菲利培
Don't feel bad about Felipe.
誰都渴望愛 親愛的
Everybody needs affection, honey.
愛讓人們舉止幼稚
Make people do funny things.
在一段感情開始的時候
人人都會這樣的
Everyone gets like that
at beginning of relationship.
奢望太多的快樂 太多的歡愉
Want too much happiness,
too much pleasure...
直到自己厭倦
...until make yourself sick.
我的感情初始之際
我 懷恩 也有這樣的感覺
Even to Wayan, this happen
at beginning of my love affair.
我失去了自我 麗茲
I lose myself, Liz.
親愛的朋友們
Dear friends and loved ones:
我的生日即將來臨
My birthday's coming up soon.
要是在家的話 我會籌備一個
無聊且昂貴的生日派對
If I were home, l'd be planning
a stupid, expensive...
你們會買禮物給我 買酒給我
...birthday party and you'd all be
buying me gifts and bottles of wine.
另一個更廉價卻更有愛的
慶祝方式是
A cheaper, more lovely way
to celebrate would be to...
捐錢給一個叫做
懷恩.諾麗亞西的大夫
...make a donation to help a healer
named Wayan Nuriyasih...
讓她在印尼買座房子
...buy a house in Indonesia.
她是個單親媽媽
在巴里島居住 離了婚
She's a single mother.
ln Bali, after a divorce...
一無所有的女人 連孩子都失去了
...a woman gets nothing,
not even her children.
為了得到她女兒圖蒂的監護權
懷恩變賣了所有的家當
To gain custody of her daughter, Tutti,
Wayan had to sell everything...
連浴室的腳墊都賣了
只為支付律師費
...even her bath mat,
to pay for a lawyer.
幾年來 她們不停的搬遷
For years,
they've moved from place to place.
每搬一次懷恩都會失去客戶
圖蒂不得不轉學
Each time, Wayan loses clientele
and Tutti has to change schools.
巴里島的這一小撮人成了我的家人
This little group of people in Bali
have become my family.
不論在哪裏和家人相遇
我們都要照顧他們
And we must take care of our
families, wherever we find them.
今天我看到圖蒂在玩
馬路上撿到的一塊藍色磁磚...
Today l saw Tutti playing with
a blue tile she'd found in the road...
...在一棟旅館興建工地附近撿到的
她和我說
...near a hotel construction site.
She told me:
或許某天我們會有個家
Maybe if we have
a house someday...
家裏鋪著這種漂亮的藍色地板
...it can have a pretty blue floor
like this.
我在意大利的時候 學到一個詞
When I was in Italy,
I learned a word--
是"圖蒂" 有兩個T
It's "tutti" with double T.
意大利語意思是"每個人"
這是我學到的一課
--which in ltalian means "everybody."
So that's the lesson, isn't it?
當你從世界出發 想幫助自己
When you set out in the world
to help yourself...
結果或許會是你幫助了圖蒂
(每個人)
...sometimes you end up
helping Tutti.
- 再說一次
- 一萬八千美金
-Tell me again.
-Eighteen thousand American dollars.
我把郵件帶來給你看了
I brought you the e-mails to look at.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
我們有家了
We get a house.
這是每個人的家!
It can be the house for everybody!
我可以擁有一間藥房! 一個圖書館!
I can have a pharmacy!
I can have a library!
- 好啦 天哪
- 再閉一次 閉上眼睛
-All right. Oh, God.
-Close them again. Close your eyes.
小心點 別磕掉牙齒了
Careful. You don't wanna
break a tooth or anything.
- 不用擔心 閉上眼睛就好
- 你要帶我去哪裏?
-Don't worry, but close your eyes.
-Where are you taking me?
你會知道的
You will see.
- 你幫助懷恩得到了一座房子
- 我知道
-You helped Wayan to get a house...
-l know.
我們得慶祝一番
...and we're going to celebrate.
- 在這裏 在這
- 好
-Here, here, here.
-All right.
- 睜眼 睜開眼吧
- 我知道我們在沙灘上 可沒帶泳衣
-Turn, turn, turn.
-l know we're at the beach.
就是這裏
Here you go.
我們要划船
We're going to take a little boat trip.
- 去哪?
Where?
- 去一座附近的小島
Where? To a little island nearby.
是我在全世界最喜歡的地方
我幫我們打點好行李了
It's my favorite place in the world.
I've packed for two.
我們可以在那裏待到下週二
在最好的野營點享受一番
We can stay there until next Tuesday.
And l have the perfect camping spot.
只有你我 和四百隻鸚鵡
Just you and l and 400 parrots.
你喜歡嗎?
Do you like it?
我本想晚上再說的
但現在時機成熟了
I was going to save it for tonight,
but I think this is the right moment.
我必須待在巴里島
是因為我的事業在這裏
I have to be in Bali
because my business is here...
你必須待在紐約
...and you have to be in New York...
是因為你的生活在那裏 對嗎?
...because that's
where your life is, right?
不如我們在這兩個地方之間
創建一種新的生活方式?
What if we tried to create a life that
is divided between the two places?
你為什麼要這樣做?
Why would you wanna do that?
因為我愛上你了
Because I'm in love with you.
- 我們走吧 我們走吧
- 不 我....
-Let's go. Let's go.
-Oh, no. I....
- 怎麼?
- 我做不到 很抱歉
-What?
-l can't. l'm sorry.
- 只不過我
- 你做不到?
-l just....
-You can't?
- 我很抱歉 我做不到
- 做不到什麼?
-l'm sorry. I can't.
-Can't what?
我現在不能出行 懂嗎 我....
I can't go on a trip right now,
okay? I....
我5天沒回家 幾周沒見科圖
I haven't been home in five days.
I haven't seen Ketut in weeks.
- 太久了
- 不算太久
-lt's just too much.
-lt's not much.
出行
To go...
雙人之旅
...by ourselves...
遠離塵囂 幾天而已
對你來說太久了嗎?
...apart from everything else for
a couple of days, is that much for you?
我不明白 問題在哪裏  麗茲?
Liz, não entendo.
What's the problem, Liz?
我心裏有恐懼 我和你受過一樣的傷
I mean, l have the same fears,
I have the same scars that you have...
我讓你看我的傷口
...and l show them to you.
你我之間唯一不同之處是
But l guess the only difference
between you and l is that...
你失去了愛的勇氣
...you are afraid to love again.
親愛的 事實擺在眼前
My darling, this is it.
你要看著我的眼睛 告訴我實情
You have to look me in the eye
and let me know the truth.
拜託了 你愛我 還是不愛?
Please. Do you love me
or do you love me not?
看著我的眼睛 告訴我
Look me in the eyes and tell me...
你愛我 還是不愛? 很簡單的
...do you love me or don't
you love me not? lt's very easy.
我知道你也有一樣的感覺
為什麼你不能說出口?
I know you feel the same way.
Why can't you say it back?
我不知道原因
I don't know why.
為什麼我不能?
Why can't l?
因為你怕 我的愛人
可是沒關係的 我也怕
Because you're terrified, my love.
But listen, it's fine. Me too.
但我還是希望可以和你一起上船
But l still want to get
into that boat with you.
- 不 你看 你看
- 什麼?
-No. Okay, look. Look.
-What?
我不知道為什麼你不懂
I don't know why
you can't understand this.
我找到某個東西 我不能放棄
I found something
and l can't give it up.
相信我 如果我放棄了
你也不會如此愛我
And trust me, if I did,
you wouldn't be so all in love with me.
好 是平衡 你環遊世界尋找你的平衡
Okay, the balance thing. You traveled
around the world to find your balance.
你以為自己找到了什麼平衡?
And the balance that you think
you've found is what?
冥想20分鐘 然後去見個老巫醫?
Meditating for 20 minutes and
going to see an old medicine man?
平衡 我的愛人啊
平衡不是讓某人愛你
Listen, balance, my darling, balance
is not letting anybody love you...
- 少於你愛自己
- 你懂什麼 你懂什麼
-...less than you love yourself.
-You know what? You know what?
不用你告訴我
我在過去一年學到什麼
Do not tell me what lessons l have
and haven't learned in the last year...
也不用告訴我 你有多平衡多睿智
...and don't tell me how balanced
and wise you are...
我表達自己有多失敗
...and how I can't express myself.
不要再叫我"親愛的"因為我不稀罕了
And do not say "darling" to me again
because l am just gonna lose it.
聽我說! 我不要通過愛你
來證明我愛自己
Listen to me! l do not need to love you
to prove that l love myself.
你要離開我嗎?
Run away from me?
你放棄了自己生命中
各種絕妙的可能
You are running away from all
the great possibilities of your own life.
我要上船了
I'm getting into that boat.
給你的
For you.
離別的禮物
A goodbye gift.
科圖
Ketut.
麗茲
Liss...
你治癒了我
...you healed me.
你也治癒了我 科圖
You healed me too, Ketut.
要不是你 我不會回到巴里島...
If it wasn't for you,
I wouldn't have come back to Bali...
或許就沒法面對自我
...and l wouldn't have come back
to myself.
你要咖啡嗎? 還是烤豬肉?
You want coffee? Roast pig?
咖啡
Coffee.
我幫你倒咖啡
I get you coffee.
你馬上就要飛回美國了嗎?
You fly back to America soon?
還有兩小時
In two hours.
你坐過飛機嗎 科圖?
Have you ever been
on an airplane, Ketut?
科圖不能坐飛機
Ketut cannot fly on aeroplane.
科圖沒有牙
Ketut have no teeths.
你是我的好朋友
You are good friend to me.
就像個女兒
You are like daughter.
我死的時候
When I die...
你會回到巴里島 看我火化嗎?
...you will come back to Bali?
Come to my cremation?
巴里島人的火化儀式很有趣的
Balinese cremation ceremony
is very fun.
- 你會喜歡的
- 好吧
-You will like it.
-Okay.
你還會像我和你說那樣開懷大笑吧
You still smile with your liver,
like l tell you?
是的
Yes.
你還會像你印度導師教導那樣冥想吧
You still meditate like your guru
in India teach you?
- 是的
- 你現在對上帝滿意嗎?
-Yes.
-You happy now with God?
- 是的
- 你愛你的新男友嗎?
-Yes.
-You love your new boyfriend?
我和他分開了
I ended it.
我不懂 為什麼你要分開?
Don't understand.
Why you do that?
我沒法保持平衡
I couldn't keep my balance.
麗茲 聽科圖的話
Liss, listen to Ketut.
有時候因愛失衡
Sometimes to lose balance
for love...
也是平衡生活的一部分
...is part of living balanced life.
在最後
In the end...
我相信了我稱之為
"尋覓物理學"的東西
...I've come to believe in something
I call "The Physics of the Quest."
一種自然界的力
就如萬有引力定律一樣真實
A force in nature governed by laws
as real as the laws of gravity.
尋覓物理學的法則是這樣的
The rule of Quest Physics
goes something like this:
如果你有足夠的勇氣
放棄所有熟悉安心的事物
If you're brave enough to leave behind
everything familiar and comforting...
這包括你的家
或是累積在心底的怨恨
...which can be anything from your
house to bitter, old resentments...
開始一段尋求真相的旅程
...and set out
on a truth-seeking journey...
無論是外在的還是內在的
...either externally or internally...
如果你真的願意
...and if you are truly willing
to regard everything...
把所有經歷看做成一種啟示
...that happens to you on that journey
as a clue...
如果你把所有遇見的人都當成導師
...and if you accept everyone you
meet along the way as a teacher...
最重要的是 如果你準備好
...and if you are prepared,
most of all...
去面對 原諒那部分並不討喜的自我
...to face and forgive some
very difficult realities about yourself...
那麼 沒人可以阻止你瞭解真相
...then the truth
will not be withheld from you.
菲利培?
Felipe?
我自身的經歷使我不由得相信
I can't help but believe it,
given my experience.
日落時分  碼頭見
我決定了屬於我的詞
I decided on my word.
意思是
It means:
"讓我們跨越過去"
"Let's cross over."